好 别急着松手
Okay, hold on, don't shoot.
瞄准了吗
You see where you're going?
好 现在我们做点儿准备
Okay. Now, let's worry about how you get there.
过来一点儿 脚尖朝这边
Gotta move your foot here. Point your toe this way.
转过来点儿
Your hips here. Okay?
- 看得见吗 - 可以
- Can you see? - Yeah.
确定吗
Are you sure?
现在呢 还看得见吗
How about now? Can you see now?
挡住啦 那这样呢
No. How about now?
行了
All right.
准备好了吗 拉弓
Ready? Three fingers.
真棒
Nice!
好球 孩子
Nice throw, kiddo.
接着
Here you go.
你们是加蛋黄酱还是芥末酱 还是都要
Hey, you guys want mayo? Or mustard? Or both?
吃热狗谁加蛋黄酱啊
Who puts mayo on a hot dog?
没准你的兄弟要
Probably your brothers.
来两个加芥末酱的 谢谢啦 亲爱的
Uh, two mustard, please! Thanks, Mama.
收到
Got it!
奈特 蛋黄酱还是芥末酱
Nate, mayo or mustard?
番茄酱怎么样
How about ketchup?
番茄酱没问题 我也有
Or ketchup. I got ketchup, too.
注意肘部
Mind your elbow.
干得好 小鹰眼 去把箭拿回来
Good job, hawk-eye. Go get your arrow.
各位 练得差不多啦 饭好啦
Hey, guys! Enough practice. Soup's on!
好的 来啦 我们都饿了
All right. We're coming. We're hungry.
莱拉 走吧
Lila, let's go.
莱拉
Lila?
亲爱的
Honey?
孩子们
Hey, babe?
亲爱的
Babe?
孩子们
Boys!
劳拉
Laura!
双语&后期
CHAOSPACE布布
更多特效字幕尽在
CHAOSPACE.FUN
你不必那样
You don't need to do that.
你保持这样就好
Because, uh, you're just holding the position.
来吧
Oh, yeah.
就差一点儿
That was close.
进了 我们现在一比一平了
That's a goal. We are now one apiece.
我想再试一次
I would like to try again.
现在平局 紧张不紧张 好玩儿吧
We're tied up. Feel the tension? It's fun.
糟糕 现在你有机会赢了
That was terrible. Now you have a chance to win.
这样你就赢了 恭喜
And you've won. Congratulations.
公平竞赛
Fair game.
友谊第一
Good sport.
好玩儿吗
You have fun?
好玩儿
It was fun.
启动了吗
This thing on?
波兹小姐 佩珀
Hey, Miss Potts. Pep.
你要是发现这段影像
If you find this recording...
可别发到网上去 这个太伤感了
don't post it on social media. It's gonna be a real tearjerker.
我不知道你能不能看见这些
I don't know if you're ever gonna see these.
我甚至不知道你是不是还…
I don't even know if you're still...
老天 希望你没事儿
Oh, God, I hope so.
今天是第二十一天了
Today's day 21.
不对 是第二十二天
No, uh, 22.
相比浩瀚的宇宙 我的存在微不足道
You know, if it wasn't for the existential terror  of staring into the literal void of space,
如果不细想 今天我过得还行
I'd say I'm feeling a little better today.
感染好多了 多亏了有蓝妹妹在这儿
Infection's run its course, thanks to the Blue Meanie back there.
你肯定会喜欢她的
Oh, you'd love her.
特别干练
Very practical.
就是下手有点儿重
Only a tiny bit sadistic.
燃料舱在作战时炸裂了
So, the fuel cells were cracked during battle...
我们想了个办法利用反向离子充电
and we figured out a way to reverse the ion charge...
争取了大概48小时的飞行时间
and bought ourselves about 48 hours of flight time.
但是现在没招了
Uh, but it's now dead in the water.
我们离最近的便利店还有几千光年呢
Thousand light years from the nearest 7-Eleven.
氧气只能支撑到明天早上
Oxygen will run out tomorrow morning...
然后就这样了
and that'll be it.
我曾经说过不会再有意外了
Pep, I know I said no more surprises...
可我真的希望能完成最后的这次任务
but I gotta say I was really hoping to pull off one last one.
但是现在看来…
But it looks like...
你也知道的
Well, you know what it looks like.
别太难过
Don't feel bad about this.
我的意思是你可以悲痛几个星期
I mean, actually, if you grovel for a couple weeks...
然后怀着自责继续生活
and then move on with enormous guilt...
我得躺下了 闭会儿眼睛
I should probably lie down for a minute. Go rest my eyes.
你要知道
Please know...
每天入睡的时候 这些天都一样
when I drift off, it'll be like every night lately.
我挺好的一切都挺好
I'm fine. Totally fine.
我会梦到你
I dream about you.
梦里一直都是你
Because it's always you.
我没能阻止他
Couldn't stop him.
我也没有
Neither could I.
那孩子牺牲了
I lost the kid.
托尼 我们都输了
Tony, we lost.
那么…
Is, uh...?
- 太好了 - 我的天
- Oh, good. - Oh, my God!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
没事儿了
It's okay.
灭霸离开地球己经二十三天了
It's been 23 days since Thanos came to Earth.
各国政府分崩离析
World governments are in pieces.
还在运转的部门正在做人口统计
The parts that are still working are trying to take a census
根据情况统计
...and it looks like he did...
看来他做的和他说的完全一致
He did exactly what he said he was gonna do.
灭霸夺走了…
Thanos wiped out...
一半的生命
...50% of all living creatures.
他现在在哪里
Where is he now? Where?
不知道
We don't know.
他打开了一扇传送门然后离开了
He just opened a portal and walked through.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
他很生气
Oh, he's pissed.
他觉得自己失败了
He thinks he failed.
确实如此 但谁不是呢
Which, of course, he did, but there's a lot of that going around, ain't there?
说真的 你不开口说话
Honestly, until this exact second
我以为你是毛绒玩具呢
I thought you were a Build-A-Bear.
随你的便
Maybe I am.
我们三周来一直在搜寻灭霸的踪迹
We've been hunting Thanos for three weeks now.
宇宙空间卫星扫描一无所获
Deep space scans and satellites, and we got nothing.
托尼 你和他交过手
Tony, you fought him.
谁告诉你的 我没和他交过手
Who told you that? I didn't fight him.
他把一颗星球砸到我脸上
No, he wiped my face with a planet...
那个变戏法的就交出原石了
while the Bleecker Street magician gave away the store.
事情就是这样 根本没法打 知道了
That's what happened. There was no fight,
打不过
'cause he's not beatable.
他有没有留下线索或坐标之类的
Did he give you any clues, any coordinates, anything?
我几年前就知道这一切
I saw this coming a few years back.
我早就料到了 我不敢相信
I had a vision. I didn't wanna believe it.
还以为是一场噩梦
Thought I was dreaming.
托尼 我需要你集中精神
Tony, I'm gonna need you to focus.
我需要过你
And I needed you.
那是以前了 比你现在更需要
As in, past tense. That trumps what you need.
一切都晚了 老兄 抱歉
It's too late, buddy. Sorry.
你知道我现在需要什么吗 我需要刮胡子
You know what I need? I need a shave.
而且我记得告诉过你们
And I believe I remember telling all youse...
托尼 托尼 托尼
Tony, Tony!
你们和那些不在的人
...alive and otherwise,
我们需要用战甲把全世界武装起来
that what we needed was a suit of armor around the world.
还记得吗
Remember that?
不管它是否侵犯了我们宝贵的自由
Whether it impacted our precious freedoms or not.
那才是我们真正需要的
That's what we needed.
那条路最后行不通
Well, that didn't work out, did it?
我说过我们会输的
I said we'd lose.
你说即使输了也一起面对
You said, "We'll do that together, too."
结果怎么样 队长 我们输了
And guess what, Cap? We lost.
而你当时根本不在
And you weren't there.
我们就这个水平吗 只能慢人一步吗
But that's what we do, right? Our best work after the fact?
我们只能当复仇者吗
We're the "Avengers."
只能当复仇者 不能当预防者吗
We're the "Avengers," not the "Pre-vengers."
- 行了 - 是不是啊
- Okay. - Right?
你说的够多了 坐下吧 好吧
You made your point. Just sit down, okay?
我还没说完
Okay. No, no, here's my point. You know what?
- 她就挺好 - 托尼 坐下吧
- She's great by the way. - Tony, you're sick. Sit down.
我们需要你 你是新生力量
We need you. You're new blood.
你们这帮老废物 我没什么可给你的
Bunch of tired old mules. I got nothing for you, Cap.
没有坐标 没有线索 没有战术 没有方案
I got no coordinates, no clues, no strategies, no options.
什么都没有 我也不相信你 你这个骗子
Zero. Zip. Nada. No trust, liar.
拿着这个
Here, take this.
你找到他以后 把这个戴上
You find him, you put that on...
然后躲起来
you hide.
- 托尼 - 我没事儿
- Tony! - I'm fine.
布鲁斯给了他一针镇静剂
Bruce gave him a sedative.
他今天可能醒不过来了
He's gonna probably be out for the rest of the day.
你们照顾好他
You guys take care of him...
我回来时给他带一瓶佐利安灵药
and I'll bring him a Xorrian elixir when I come back.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
去杀灭霸
To kill Thanos.
我们一般都是团队作战
You know, we usually work as a team here...
再说现在士气也不高
and, uh, between you and I, morale's a little fragile.
我们知道太空是你的地盘
We realize up there is more your territory,
但这也是我们的战斗
but this is our fight, too.
你知道他到底在哪儿吗
You even know where he is?
我找人问就行
I know people who might.
没必要
Don't bother.
我可以告诉你们灭霸在哪里
I can tell you where Thanos is.
灭霸用了很长时间使我变得完美
Thanos spent a long time trying to perfect me.
他一直在给我讲述那个宏大的计划
And when he worked, he talked about his Great Plan.
即便被大卸八块 我也想讨好他
Even disassembled, I wanted to please him.
我就会问…
I'd ask...
大功告成以后 我们将何去何从
where would we go once his plan was complete?
他的回答永远只有一个
And his answer was always the same.
去那个花园
"To the Garden."
真够可以的 灭霸居然还有退休计划
That's cute. Thanos has a retirement plan.
所以他在哪儿
So, where is he?
灭霸打完响指后
When Thanos snapped his fingers...
地球成了宇宙级能量涌动的原爆点
Earth became ground zero for a power surge of ridiculously cosmic proportions.
从没有过这么大的能量
No one's ever seen anything like it.
直到两天以前
Until two days ago...
在这颗星球上
on this planet.
灭霸就在那里
Thanos is there.
他又用原石了
He used the stones again.
我们现在人手短缺吧
We'd be going in shorthanded, you know?
而且原石还在他手上 所以…
Look, he's still got the stones, so...
那就抢回来
So, let's get 'em.
把所有人救回来
Use them to bring everyone back.
就这么简单吗
Just like that?
对 就这么简单
Yeah. Just like that.
即便逆转这一切的希望渺茫
Even if there's a small chance that we can undo this...
为了逝去的战友 我们也必须竭尽全力去试试
I mean, we owe it to everyone who's not in this room to try.
如果我们这么做了
If we do this, how do we know
我们怎么知道结局会和之前不一样
it's gonna end any differently than it did before?
因为之前你们没有我
Because before you didn't have me.
嘿 新来的
Hey, new girl?
这个屋子里的人多少也都算超级英雄
Everybody in this room is about that superhero life.
我倒要问问这么长时间你去哪儿了
And if you don't mind my asking, where the hell have you been all this time?
宇宙里的星球很多
There are a lot of other planets in the universe.
可惜没有你们这样的人守护
And unfortunately, they didn't have you guys.
我觉得她不错
I like this one.
我们去干掉这个混蛋
Let's go get this son of a bitch.
复
仇
者
联
盟
终
局
之
战
好吧 谁没来过太空
Okay. Who here hasn't been to space?
怎么了
Why?
可别在我的船上吐出来
You better not throw up on my ship.
启动跳跃 三 二一
Approaching jump in three, two, one.
我先去侦察一下
I'll head down for recon.
我们会成功的 史蒂夫
This is gonna work, Steve.
我知道
I know it will.
除了成功我别无选择
'Cause I don't know what I'm gonna do if it doesn't.
没有卫星 没有舰船
No satellites. No ships. No armies.
没有军队 没有任何地面防御
No ground defenses of any kind.
只有他一个人
It's just him.
那就够了
And that's enough.
不
Oh, no.
原石在哪里
Where are they?
回答他的问题
Answer the question.
宇宙需要被校正
The universe required correction.
在那之后 原石除了诱惑再无他用
After that, the stones served no purpose beyond temptation.
你杀害了无数生命
You murdered trillions!
你们应该为之感恩
You should be grateful.
原石在哪里
Where are the stones?
不在了 一切归为尘埃
Gone. Reduced to atoms.
你两天前才刚刚用过
You used them two days ago!
我使用原石摧毁了原石
I used the stones to destroy the stones.
这几乎要了我的命
It nearly killed me.
但我的使命完成了
But the work is done.
注定如此
It always will be.
我就是…天命
I am inevitable.
我们好好找找 他肯定在说谎
We have to tear this place apart. He has to be lying!
我父亲什么都干得出来
My father is many things.
但他从不说谎
A liar is not one of them.
谢谢你 女儿
Thank you, daughter.
也许我对你太苛刻了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly.
什么
What?
你干了什么
What did you do?
这次我是冲着头去的
I went for the head.
五
年
后
所以 我…
So...
他们不在了,
我们何去何从?
我约人出去吃了个饭
...I, uh, went on a date the other day.
五年以来第一次
It's the first time in five years.
我坐在餐桌那里 不知道该说些什么
You know? I'm sitting there at dinner. I didn't even know what to talk about.
你们聊了什么
What did you talk about?
还是那些废话 一切都变了
Eh, same old crap. You know, how things have changed.
我的工作 他的工作
My job, his job.
我们有多么想念大都会球队
How much we miss the Mets.
后来我们都沉默了
And then things got quiet...
然后他在上沙拉的时候哭了
then he cried as they were serving the salads.
那你呢
What about you?
我也哭了 在上甜点的时候
I cried just before dessert.
但是我们明天还会见面 所以…
But I'm seeing him again tomorrow, so...
很好 你克服了最艰难的时刻
That's great.
虽然不知道结果会怎么样
You did the hardest part. You took the jump.
你还是迈出了新的一步
You didn't know where you were gonna come down.
就是这样 我们总要迈出这样的一小步
And that's it. That's those little brave baby steps we gotta take...
让我们重新振作起来 重新找到方向
to try and become whole again, try and find purpose.
1945年我被封在冰里
I went in the ice in '45,
那之前我刚遇到一生至爱
right after I met the love of my life.
直到七十年后我才醒来
Woke up 70 years later.
但是你必须要继续前行
You gotta move on.
继续生活
Gotta move on.
世界的命运在你我手中
The world is in our hands.
这是我们的使命 我们责无旁贷
It's left to us, guys. And we gotta do something with it.
否则…
Otherwise...
灭霸本可以杀掉我们所有人
Thanos should've killed all of us.
旧 金 山
个人仓库
怎么回事儿
What the hell?
霍普
Hope?
保安
救命
寻人启事
孩子 孩子
Kid! Hey, kid!
这里发生了什么
What the hell happened here?
消逝的人
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
不要 不要 不不不
Oh, please! Please, please!
不
No, no, no. No.
No.
让一让 不好意思
Excuse me. Sorry.
凯茜 不
Oh, Cassie, no.
不要 不要 不要 不 不
No, no, no. No, no.
不要有凯茜
Please, please, please. No, Cassie.
斯科特·朗
什么
What?
凯茜
Cassie?
爸爸
Dad?
你都长这么大了
You're so big!
限制区域 闲人免进
好吧 我们己经登上丹佛斯发现的那艘可疑的飞船了
Yeah. We boarded that highly-suspect warship Danvers pinged.
其实就是一艘破烂垃圾船
It was an infectious garbage scow.
谢谢你提供这么有用的情报
So, thanks for the hot tip.
当时你们离得最近
Well, you were closer.
现在我们还一身垃圾味儿
Yeah. And now we smell like garbage.
那些震动是怎么回事儿
You get a reading on those tremors?
就是非洲板块的地壳运动而己
'Twas a mild subduction under the African plate.
有影像吗 你们是怎么处理的
Do we have a visual? How are we handling it?
娜塔莎 那就是个海底地震
Nat. It's an earthquake under the ocean.
我们根本就不用管
We handle it by not handling it.
卡罗尔 下个月你还在吗
Carol, are we seeing you here next month?
不一定
Not likely.
什么 你又要去美发吗
What? You gonna get another haircut?
听着 小毛脸 我要负责的范围很大
Listen, fur face. I'm covering a lot of territory.
和地球有同样遭遇的星球
The things that are happening on Earth are happening everywhere.
至少有几千颗
On thousands of planets.
好吧 你说的对 说的没错
All right, all right. That's a good point. That's a good point.
所以我可能要缺席一段时间
So, you might not see me for a long time.
好吧 这个频道会一直开着
All right. Uh, well. This channel's always active.
所以如果出了什么差错
So, if anything goes sideways...
或者谁又在制造什么麻烦 记得联系我
anyone's making trouble where they shouldn't comes through me.
没问题 好的
Okay.
好
All right.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
墨西哥
Mexico.
警方发现了一个屋子 里面全是尸体
The Federales found a room full of bodies.
应该是一群黑帮 都没来得及还手
Looks like a bunch of cartel guys never even had a chance to get their guns off.
说不定是黑吃黑
It's probably a rival gang.
肯定不是 这绝对是巴顿干的
Except it isn't. It's definitely Barton.
他在这里的所作所为
What he's done here...
和他过去几年的行径
what he's been doing for the last few years...
还有他造成的那些影响
I mean, the scene that he left...
其实我真的有点儿不想找到他
I gotta tell you, there's a part of me that doesn't even wanna find him.
你能查出来他接下来的去向吗
Will you find out where he's going next?
娜塔莎
Nat?
帮个忙
Please?
好吧
Okay.
我本打算给你做晚餐的
You know, I'd offer to cook you dinner...
但看来你己经够惨了
but you seem pretty miserable already.
你是来洗衣服的
You here to do your laundry?
顺便再看个朋友
And to see a friend.
你的朋友一切都好
Clearly, your friend is fine.
我那天在过桥的时候看到一群鲸
You know, I saw a pod of whales when I was coming over the bridge.
- 哈德逊河吗 - 没什么船 水也清澈
In the Hudson? There's fewer ships...cleaner water.
如果你要让我去积极的面对生活
You know, if you're about to tell me to look on the bright side...
我就把三明治砸在你脸上
I'm about to hit you in the head with a peanut butter sandwich.
对不起 习惯了
Sorry. Force of habit.
我一直在告诉每一个人生活还要继续
You know, I keep telling everybody they should move on...
学会成长
and grow.
有的人可以
Some do.
但我们不会
But not us.
如果我继续生活 谁来做这些
If I move on, who does this?
也许根本没必要去做
Maybe it doesn't need to be done.
我曾经一无所有
I used to have nothing.
然后我得到了这个
And then I got this.
这份工作
This job.
这个家庭
This family.
而且我…因为这些变得更好了
And I was better because of it.
即便这一切都不在了
And even though they're gone...
我也在试着变得更好
I'm still trying to be better.
我觉得我们都需要新的生活
I think we both need to get a life.
你先来
You first.
你好 你好 有人在吗
Oh, hi, hi! Uh, is anyone home?
我是斯科特·朗
This is, uh, Scott Lang.
我们几年前在机场见过 在德国
We met a few years ago at the airport in Germany?
我就是那个巨人 我当时戴了个面具
I was the guy that got really big. I had a mask on.
- 记得吗 - 过去的画面吗
You wouldn't recognize me. Is this an old message?
蚁人 你们听说过蚁人吧
Ant-Man? I know you know that.
正门监控
It's the front gate.
我有话要和你们说
I really need to talk to you guys.
你可以的 可以的
You can, you can...
斯科特
Scott.
你没事儿吧
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
你们有谁学过量子物理吗
Have either of you guys ever studied quantum physics?
仅限聊天
Only to make conversation.
那好吧
All right, so...
五年前 就在灭霸那件事之前
five years ago, right before...Thanos...
我在一个叫做量子领域的地方
I was in a place called the quantum realm.
量子领域就像是一个独立的微缩宇宙
The quantum realm is like its own microscopic universe.
要想进去你得变得特别特别小
To get in there, you have to be incredibly small.
霍普 她是我的…
Hope. She's my, um...
她曾经是我的…
She was my...
她本来应该把我拉出来
She was supposed to pull me out.
然后灭霸出现了 我就被困在那里了
And then Thanos happened...and I got stuck in there.
这肯定是很漫长的五年吧
I'm sorry, that must have been a very long five years.
这就是我要说的 其实不长
Yeah, but that's just it. It wasn't.
对于我而言就是五个小时而己
For me, it was five hours.
量子领域的规则和这个世界不太一样
See, the rules of the quantum realm aren't like they are up here.
一切都是变幻莫测的
Everything is unpredictable.
那是谁的三明治 我快饿死了
Is that anybody's sandwich? I'm starving.
斯科特 你在说什么
Scott. What are you talking about?
其实…
So...
我要说的是…
what I'm saying is...
量子领域的时间机制是不一样的
time works differently in the quantum realm.
现在唯一的问题是我们没法操控它
The only problem is right now we don't have a way to navigate it.
如果可以呢 我一直在想
But what if we did? I can't stop thinking about it.
如果我们能够控制这种混乱呢
What if we could somehow control the chaos and we could navigate it?
如果我们可以在某个特定的时间点进入量子领域
What if there was a way that we could enter the quantum realm at a certain point in time...
然后在另一个时间点从量子领域出来呢
but then exit the quantum realm at another point in time?
比如…
Like...
- 在灭霸来之前 - 等等
- Like before Thanos. - Wait.
你说的是时间机器吗
Are you talking about a time machine?
不 当然不是 不是时间机器
No. No, of course not. No, not a time machine.
这更像是一个
This is more like a...
对 就是时间机器
Yeah. Like a time machine.
我知道 这很疯狂 太疯狂了
I know, it's crazy. It's crazy.
但是我一直在想 肯定有…
But I can't stop thinking about it. There's gotta be...
有办法的
some way...
- 这太疯狂了 - 斯科特
- It's crazy. - Scott.
浣熊都能给我发邮件呢
I get emails from a raccoon...
这没什么疯狂可言
so nothing sounds crazy anymore.
那我们该去找谁商量
So, who do we talk to about this?
吃饭时间到了
Chow time!
摩小根
Maguna.
摩根·史塔克 想吃午餐吗
Morgan H. Stark, you want some lunch?
- 交出午餐 否则后果自负 - 好吧
-  Define "lunch" or be disintegrated. -  Okay.
你可不能戴这个
You should not be wearing that, okay?
这是我给妈妈准备的周年礼物
That is part of a special anniversary gift I'm making for Mom.
我看看 午餐想吃什么
There you go. You thinking about lunch?
我可以给你用生菜卷些蟋蟀什么的
I can give you a handful of crickets on a bed of lettuce.
- 不要 - 想不想试试
- No. - That's what you want.
你是从哪找到这个的
How did you find this?
- 车库里 - 真的吗
- Garage. - Really?
- 你是专门去找的 - 不是
Were you looking for it? No.
但是我就是找到了
I found it, though.
你喜欢去车库是不是 爸爸也喜欢
You like going in the garage, huh? So does Daddy.
其实没关系 反正给你妈妈 她也不会戴
It's fine, actually. Mom never wears anything I buy her.
接下来我要…
So, I'm gonna...
不 我们知道这听起来有点儿夸张
No. We know what it sounds like.
经历了这么多事以后 还有什么不可能的吗
Tony, after everything you've seen, is anything really impossible?
量子波动打破普朗克尺度
Quantum fluctuation messes with the Planck scale...
然后触发德式效应 是这个意思吗
which then triggers the Deutsch Proposition. Can we agree on that?
谢谢
Thank you.
简而言之 就是你回不来的
In layman's terms, it means you're not coming home.
- 我回来了 - 不
- I did. - No.
你是侥幸活下来的
You accidentally survived.
这是几十亿分之一的概率
It's a billion-to-one cosmic fluke.
然后现在你还想要… 叫什么来着
And now you wanna pull a... What do you call it?
时空劫持
A time heist?
对 时空劫持
Yeah, a time heist. Of course.
没错 我们以前怎么没想到
Why didn't we think of this before?
因为这太荒谬了 因为这就是白日做梦
Oh, because it's laughable. Because it's a pipe dream.
原石在过去
The stones are in the past.
我们回到过去就可以得到它们
We could go back, we could get them.
我们也可以打响指 然后把所有人带回来
We can snap our own fingers. We can bring everybody back.
也没准比现在的结果更糟糕
Or screw it up worse than he already has, right?
我觉得不会
I don't believe we would.
这种盲目的乐观还真是久违了
Gotta say it. I sometimes miss that giddy optimism.
但是心气再高也没用
However, high hopes won't help...
如果没有一个切实可行的方法
if there's no logical, tangible way
就无法安全执行
for me to safely execute said time heist.
时空劫持 最有可能的结果
I believe the most likely outcome
是全军覆没
will be our collective demise.
只要严格遵守时间旅行的规则就可以吧
Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel.
不和过去的自己交谈
All right? It means no talking to our past selves...
不在任何体育比赛里下注…
no betting on sporting events.
就此打住 斯科特
I'm gonna stop you right there, Scott.
你真的觉得拯救宇宙的计划
Are you seriously telling me that your plan to save the universe...
就是照抄《回到未来》吗
is based on Back to the Future? Is it?
不
No.
那就好 吓着我了
Good. You had me worried there.
那是胡编的
'Cause that would be horseshit.
量子物理可不是这样的
That's not how quantum physics works.
托尼
Tony.
我们得坚守立场
We have to take a stand.
我们坚守过了 但就是现在的结果
We did stand. And yet, here we are.
我知道你有很多顾虑
I know you got a lot on the line.
你有一个妻子 有一个女儿
You got a wife, a daughter.
但我失去了对我很重要的人
But I lost someone very important to me.
很多人都一样 可现在
A lotta people did.
现在有机会把她带回来
And now, now we have a chance to bring her back...
把所有人带回来
to bring everyone back,
你居然都不愿意…
and you're telling me that you won't even...
没错 斯科特 我不愿意
That's right, Scott. I won't even.
我做不到
I can't.
妈妈让我来救你
Mommy told me to come and save you.
干得好 我得救了
Good job. I'm saved.
你们想要干点别的什么都行
I wish you were coming here to ask me something else. Anything else.
见到你们真的很开心
I'm honestly happy to see you guys, I just...
一块吃饭吧
Oh, look, the table's set for six.
托尼 我知道
Tony. I get it.
我真的为你感到高兴
And I'm happy for you. I really am.
但我们还有第二次机会
But this is a second chance.
这里就是我的第二次机会 队长
I got my second chance right here, Cap.
我不能再去冒险了
Can't roll the dice on it.
留下来吃午餐吧 我们聊点儿别的
If you don't talk shop, you can stay for lunch.
他害怕了
Well, he's scared.
他并没有错
He's not wrong.
但是我们应该怎么办
Yeah, but, I mean, what are we gonna do?
我们需要他 就这样放弃吗
We need him. What, are we gonna stop?
不放弃 但是稳妥起见
No, I wanna do it right.
得再找个高手
We're gonna need a really big brain.
比他还高吗
Bigger than his?
吃呀 怎么就我一个人吃啊
Come on, I feel like I'm the only one eating here.
尝尝这个
Try some of that.
来点儿鸡蛋
Have some eggs.
我很不能理解
I'm so confused.
不能理解的事儿多着呢
These are confusing times.
不 我不是那个意思
Right, no, no. That's not what I meant.
没事儿 我明白 开个玩笑而己
Nah, I get it. I'm kidding!
我知道这很夸张
I know, it's crazy.
我都开始穿外衣了
I'm wearing shirts now.
对 这是怎么回事儿 为什么会这样
Yeah. What? How? Why?
五年前我们一败涂地
Five years ago, we got our asses beat.
而且对我而言更加刻骨铭心
Except it was worse for me 'cause I lost twice.
先是浩克输了 然后班纳也输了
First, Hulk lost, then Banner lost...
最后我们全输了
and then, we all lost.
没有人责备你 布鲁斯
No one blamed you, Bruce.
我很自责
I did.
这么多年我一直把浩克当成某种疾病
For years, I've been treating the Hulk like he's some kind of disease...
一直想办法根除
something to get rid of.
但是后来我试着把他看作解药
But then, I start looking at him as the cure.
在伽马实验室里待了18个月以后
Eighteen months in the gamma lab.
我把智慧和力量合二为一
I put the brains and the brawn together...
你看 这就是二者的完美结合
and now, look at me. Best of both worlds.
- 不好意思 浩克先生 - 怎么
- Excuse me, Mr. Hulk? - Yes.
我们能合个影吗
Can we get a photo?
百分之百可以 小朋友
100%, little person.
过来 靠近点儿 你能帮个忙吗
Come on, step on up. Do you mind?
- 没问题 - 多谢
- Oh, yeah, yeah. - Thanks.
来 说绿茄子
Say "green."
绿茄子
- Green. - Green.
拍好了吗
Did you get that?
拍好了
That's a good one.
你们要跟我合影吗 我是蚁人
Did you want to grab one with me? I'm Ant-Man.
他们是浩克粉 他们根本不知道蚁人是谁
They're Hulk fans. They don't know Ant-Man.
- 没关系 大家都不知道 - 别啊 他想合影
- Nobody does. - No, he wants you to take
- 想不想跟他合影 - 我不想拍照
a picture with him. I don't want a picture.
陌生人不安全
Stranger danger.
人家都说不拍了
Yeah, look, he's even saying no, he doesn't.
没关系 无所谓的
I get it. I don't want it, either.
别啊 看孩子们
But come on. The kid...
不用跟我合影了
I don't want a picture with them.
- 他会不开心的 - 不好意思
He's gonna feel bad. Sorry.
其实他们愿意 没问题
They're happy to do it. They said they'll do it.
- 我不想 - 我们可以
I don't want to do it. We can do it.
- 不 你 你不开心 - 把这个破手机拿走
- No, you feel bad. - Take the goddamn phone.
好的
Okay.
谢谢你 浩克
Thank you, Mr. Hulk.
孩子们 非常感谢你们
No, it was great, kids. Thank you very much.
浩克出击
Hulk out!
布鲁斯
Bruce.
耍个帅
Dab.
- 布鲁斯 - 要听妈妈的话
Bruce. Listen to your mom.
她说的都对
She knows better.
我们回到正题
About what we were saying.
好的
Right.
时空穿梭那一套
The whole time travel do-over?
这真的不是我的专业领域
Eh, guys, it's outside of my area of expertise.
你都把自己变成这样了
Well, you pulled this off.
好像以前这也是不可能的吧
I remember a time when that seemed pretty impossible, too.
我有个小灵感 看看能不能行得通
I've got a mild inspiration. I'd like to see if it checks out.
所以在今晚收工以前再模拟一次
So, I'd like to run one last sim before we pack it in for the night.
这一回在莫比乌斯环里 翻转过来
This time, in the shape of a Mobius strip, inverted, please.
正在处理
Processing.
给我那个粒子的特征值
Right, give me the eigenvalue of that particle...
还有它在光谱分析中的反应
factoring in spectral decomp.
- 可能得费点儿工夫 - 请稍候
- That'll take a second. - Just a moment.
不成功也无所谓 随便试试
And don't worry if it doesn't pan out. I'm just kinda...
模型渲染完毕
Model rendered.
建模 成功
该死
Shit!
你怎么还没睡 小公主
What are you doing up, little miss?
- 该死 - 不行 不能这么说话
- Shit. - Nope. We don't say that.
只有妈妈可以说那个词
Only Mommy says that word.
那是她发明的 她的专属词
She coined it. It belongs to her.
你怎么还不睡
Why are you up?
因为我有该死的大事要做
'Cause I've got some important shit going on here!
要不然呢
Why do you think?
不不 我心里有些事放不下
No, I got something on my mind.
我在想事情
I got something on my mind.
你想的是果汁冰棍吗
Was it juice pops?
你猜对了
Sure was.
你这就是敲诈 一点儿没错
That's extortion. That's a word.
你想要什么样的
What kind you want?
英雄所见略同
Great minds think alike.
果汁冰棍 毫无疑问 我想的…
Juice pops exactly...
就是这个
was on my mind.
你还吃吗
You done? Yeah?
现在没有了
Now you are.
擦擦嘴
Here. Wipe.
好 躺下去
Good. That face goes there.
给我讲个故事
Tell me a story.
讲故事
A story.
很久很久以前摩小根睡着了 讲完
Once upon a time, Maguna went to bed. The end.
这故事太无聊了
That is a horrible story.
这可是你最喜欢的故事啊
Come on, that's your favorite story.
爱你一千遍
Love you tons.
那我爱你三千遍
I love you 3,000.
天啊
Wow.
三千遍 这数可真大
3,000. That's crazy.
赶紧睡觉 否则我把你的玩具全卖了
Go to bed or I'll sell all your toys.
晚安
Night night.
我不是想炫耀 但是她说爱我三千遍
Not that it's a competition, but she loves me 3,000.
她说的吗
Does she, now?
你可能大概只有600到900遍左右
You were somewhere in the low 6 to 900 range.
你在读什么
Whatcha reading?
就是一本关于有机肥的书
Just a book on composting.
有机肥有什么新鲜的吗
What's new with composting?
- 科学真是奇妙… - 我搞定了
- Interesting science... - I figured it out.
顺便告诉你一下
By the way.
我们在聊的是一件事吗
And, you know, just so we're talking about the same thing...
时空穿梭
Time travel.
什么
What?
天啊
Wow.
不可思议
That's amazing...
还有点儿吓人
and terrifying.
没错
That's right.
我们真的很幸运
We got really lucky.
是 我知道
Yeah. I know.
很多人没那么幸运
A lot of people didn't.
我帮不了所有人
Nope. And I can't help everybody.
其实也许你可以
Sorta seems like you can.
我不帮就是了
Not if I stop.
我可以立刻收手 完全不管
I can put a pin in it right now and stop.
托尼
Tony...
劝你收手
trying to get you to stop...
我估计这辈子都做不到了
has been one of the few failures of my entire life.
我觉得我应该闭口不谈这件事儿
Something tells me...
把它忘个一干二净
I should put it in a lockbox and drop it to the bottom of the lake...
然后上床休息
and go to bed.
但是你能安心休息吗
But would you be able to rest?
准备开始 第一次时空穿梭测试
Okay, here we go. Time travel test number one.
斯科特 启动那个…
Scott, fire up...
车里的东西
the, uh, van thing.
断路器己设置
Breakers are set.
紧急发电机己就绪
Emergency generators are on standby.
很好 如果突然断电了
Good, because if we blow the grid,
我可不想把这小人儿丢在上世纪五十年代
I don't want to lose, uh, Tiny here in the 1950s.
- 你说什么 - 他在开玩笑
- Excuse me? - He's kidding.
别瞎说
You can't say things like that.
开个玩笑而己
It was a bad joke.
你是在开玩笑吗
You were kidding, right?
我也不知道 现在谈论的可是时空穿梭
I have no idea. We're talking about time travel here.
要么是开玩笑 要么是真玩儿完
Either it's all a joke, or none of it is.
我们准备好了
We're good!
戴上头盔吧
Get your helmet on.
斯科特 我要把你送回一周前
Scott, I'm gonna send you back a week...
让你在那边逛上一小时
let you walk around for an hour,
然后10秒钟以后带你回来
then bring you back in 10 seconds.
明白了吗
Make sense?
完全理解
Perfectly not confusing.
祝你好运 斯科特 你行的
Good luck, Scott. You got this.
没错 我肯定行 美国队长
You're right. I do, Captain America.
三秒倒计时
On a count of three...
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
各位 我觉得好像有点儿不对劲
Uh... Guys? This doesn't feel right.
这是怎么
What is this?
- 这是怎么回事儿 - 那是谁
- What's going on? - Who is that?
- 稍等一下 - 斯科特吗
Hold on. Is that Scott?
对 是我斯科特
Yes, it's Scott.
- 发生什么了 布鲁斯 - 我的后背
- What's going on, Bruce? - Oh, my back!
- 这又是怎么回事儿 - 稍等一下
- What is this? - Hold on a second.
给我让开点儿地方
Could I get a little space here?
行行行 你能把他带回来吗
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Can you bring him back?
我正在努力
I'm working on it.
这是个婴儿
It's a baby.
- 这是斯科特 - 对 婴儿般的
- It's Scott. - As a baby.
- 他会长大的 - 把斯科特带回来
- He'll grow. - Bring Scott back.
我说关掉电源就立刻关掉
When I say kill the power, kill the power.
天哪
Oh, my God.
关掉
And... kill it!
我的裤子被尿湿了
Somebody peed my pants.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
不知道是婴儿的我 还是老年的我
But I don't know if it was baby me or old me.
也许就是现在的我
Or just me me.
时空穿梭
Time travel!
怎么了
What?
我觉得这可是大获全胜
I see this as an absolute win.
为什么拉着个长脸
Why the long face?
让我猜一下 他是不是变成婴儿了
Let me guess, he turned into a baby.
还变成了其他的 你来这儿有何贵干
Among other things, yeah. What are you doing here?
这就是爱波罗悖论
It's the EPR Paradox.
朗没有在时间中穿梭
Instead of pushing Lang through time,
而是时间在朗体内穿梭
you might've wound up pushing time through Lang.
很复杂 也很危险
It's tricky, dangerous.
本来应该有人警告你们的
Somebody could have cautioned you against it.
你警告过我们
You did.
我警告过吗 谢天谢地我来了
Oh, did I? Well, thank God I'm here.
不管怎么样 我搞定了
Regardless, I fixed it.
一个功能完备的时空穿梭导航器
A fully functioning time-space GPS.
我们干脆讲和吧
I just want peace.
结仇消耗太多精力 我不喜欢这样
Turns out resentment is corrosive, and I hate it.
我也不喜欢
Me, too.
我们可以再去冒险
We got a shot at getting these stones,
但是我得先说好 什么对我最重要
but I gotta tell you my priorities.
我希望可以扭转一切
Bring back what we lost, I hope, yes.
但前提是要保住我现在拥有的一切
Keep what I found, I have to, at all costs.
要是还能不那么玩命就更好了
And maybe not die trying would be nice.
那就说定了
Sounds like a deal.
托尼 我受之有愧
Tony, I don't know.
为什么
Why?
他专门为你造的
He made it for you.
我得把它从车库里弄出来
Plus, honestly, I have to get it out of the garage
否则摩根就拿去滑着玩儿了
before Morgan takes it sledding.
谢谢你 托尼
Thank you, Tony.
你能稍微低调点儿吗
Will you keep that a little quiet?
我可没给所有人都准备礼物
Didn't bring one for the whole team.
所有人都来了吧
We are getting the whole team, yeah?
我们正在努力
We're working on that right now.
嘿 哥们儿
Hey, Humie.
绿大个儿在哪儿
Where's Big Green?
应该在厨房吧
The kitchen, I think.
挺带劲儿
That's awesome.
罗德 回来的时候小心点儿
Rhodey, careful on re-entry.
降落区有个白痴
There's an idiot in the landing zone.
吓我一跳
Oh, God.
吓成正常尺寸了吗
What's up, Regular-Sized Man?
我想带你随便转转
♪Let me take you on a litte trip♪
音速飞船任你差遣
♪My supersonic ship's at your disposal♪
只要你是心甘情愿
♪If you feel so inclined well♪
好吗
♪Alright♪
欢迎来到新阿斯加德
乘着飞船超越光速
♪We're gonna travel faster than light♪
穿上外套裹紧衣服
请你决定去往何处
♪And you'll go anywhere you want to decide well♪
好吗
♪Alright♪
尘世凡人并肩前行
♪To many people side by side♪
这里和金色宫殿与魔法锤子什么的
Kind of a step down from the golden palaces
根本比不了啊
and the magic hammers and whatnot.
哥们儿 有点儿同情心吧
Hey, have a little compassion, pal.
首先他们失去了阿斯加德 然后又失去了半数的人民
First, they lost Asgard, then half their people.
有个地方落脚 己经很满足了
They're probably just happy to have a home.
你们来这儿干什么
You shouldn't have come.
女武神
Valkyrie!
见到你真开心 疯丫头
Great to see you, angry girl!
我觉得你哪个模样都比现在强
I think I liked you better either of the other ways.
这是火箭
This is Rocket.
你好 美女
How ya doing?
他不会见你们的
He won't see you.
这么糟糕啊
It's that bad, huh?
我们一个月只能见他一次
We only see him once a month
那一天他会出来拿补给
when he comes in for "supplies."
麦芽酒 啤酒 黑啤酒
这么糟糕
It's that bad.
是啊
Yeah.
天啊
What the...?
什么东西死在这儿了
Whew! Something died in here!
你在吗 索尔
Hello? Thor!
你们是来修有线电视的吗
Are you here about the cable?
两周以前电影频道不能看了
The Cinemax went out two weeks ago...
体育节目也不清楚
and the sports are all kinda fuzzy and whatnot.
索尔
Thor?
兄弟们 天啊
Boys! Oh, my God!
天啊 见到你们真高兴
Oh, my God, it's so good to see you!
过来 你这个可爱的小捣蛋鬼
Come here, cuddly little rascal.
- 我挺好的 - 我挺好的
- Yeah, no, I'm good. - I'm good.
别摸了 差不多行了
That's not necessary.
浩克 你认识我的朋友米克和科恩格吧
Hulk, you know my friends Miek and Korg, right?
哥们儿
- Hey, boys! - Hey, guys.
好久不见
Long time no see.
啤酒在桶里 无线网络随便用
Beer's in the bucket. Feel free to log on to the Wi-Fi.
直接连 没密码
No password, obviously.
索尔 他又来了
Thor, he's back.
电视上那个小子刚才又骂我蠢货了
That kid on the TV just called me a dickhead again.
菜鸟至尊
Noobmaster.
对 菜鸟至尊六九说我是蠢货
Yeah, NoobMaster69 called me a dickhead.
这回看我的
I am sick of this.
菜鸟至尊 还是我 雷霆之神索尔
Noobmaster, hey, it's Thor again. You know, the God of Thunder.
听好了 如果你不立刻从游戏里下线
Listen, bud, if you don't log off this game immediately...
我就要飞到你们家去
I am gonna fly over to your house,
找到你藏身的地下室
come down to that basement you're hiding in...
扯下你的胳膊 弄到你屁股里去
rip off your arms, and shove them up your butt!
没错 去和你爸爸哭去吧 你这个胆小鬼
Oh, that's right, yes! Go cry to your father, you little weasel.
谢谢你 索尔
Thank you, Thor.
他要是再招惹你 告诉我
Let me know if he bothers you again, okay?
太谢谢你了 我会的
Thank you very much. I will.
你们想喝一杯吗 喝点儿什么
So, you guys want a drink? What are we drinking?
有啤酒 龙舌兰 什么都有
I've got beer, tequila, all sorts of things.
哥们儿 你还好吗
Buddy. You all right?
我很好 怎么了
Yes, I'm fine. Why?
我看上去不好吗
Why, don't I look all right?
你看上去像一滩化了的冰淇淋
You look like melted ice cream.
怎么着 你们是来这儿玩的还是什么
So, what's up? You just here for a hang, or what?
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
我们可能有机会修复这一切
There might be a chance we could fix everything.
你说的是有线电视吗
What, like the cable?
那玩意儿己经折腾我好几个星期了
'Cause that's been driving me bananas for weeks.
我说的是灭霸
Like Thanos.
不许提那个名字
Don't say that name.
没错 我们在这儿从来不提那个名字
Um, yeah, we don't actually say that name in here.
请松开你的手
Please take your hand off me.
我知道 那家伙可能是你内心的恐惧
Now, I know that guy might scare you.
凭什么
Why would I be...?
那家伙有什么可怕的
Why would I be scared of that guy?
是我亲手杀了那个家伙 你忘了
I'm the one who killed that guy, remember?
还有谁杀得了他吗
Anyone else here kill that guy?
没有 我认为没有
Nope. Didn't think so.
科恩格 你怎么不提醒一下大家
Korg, why don't you, uh, tell everybody
是谁砍了灭霸的脑袋
who chopped Thanos' big head off?
是暴风战斧吗
Um, Stormbreaker?
那是谁在挥舞暴风战斧
Who was swinging Stormbreaker?
我知道 你正在痛苦挣扎
I get it. You're in a rough spot, okay?
我也曾经这样过
I've been there myself.
你知道是谁帮我走出来的吗
And you want to know who helped me out of it?
是娜塔莎吗
Was it Natasha?
是你
It was you.
你帮助了我
You helped me.
那你怎么不去…
So, why don't you ask...
问问那些阿斯加德人
the Asgardians down there...
我的帮助有什么价值
how much my help is worth?
反正他们都己经不在了
The ones that are left, anyway.
也许我们可以把他们带回来
I think we could bring them back.
住口
Stop.
给我住口
Stop, okay?
你们觉得我是在这儿自怨自艾
I know you think I'm down here wallowing in my own self-pity...
等待援助或救赎什么的
waiting to be rescued and saved...
但是我挺好的 我们挺好的 是不是
but I'm fine, okay. We're fine, aren't we?
我们都很好 朋友
Oh, we're good here, mate.
所以不管你们说什么 我们都不去
So, whatever it is that you're offering, we're not into it.
不在乎 也没法在乎
Don't care. Couldn't care less.
再见
Goodbye.
我们需要你 哥们儿
We need you, pal.
飞船上有啤酒
There's beer on the ship.
什么牌子的
What kind?
东 京
他在哪儿 干掉他
是他 他在追明彦
浪人在这里
他在那儿
你为什么要这么做？
我们和你无冤无仇
你们活了下来
半个星球的人都死了
他们遇到的是灭霸
你们遇到的是我…
你们休想再继续滥杀无辜了
我们滥杀无辜？
你疯了
去死吧
等等 饶命
我什么都给你
你想要什么？
我想要的你给不了我
What I want you can't give me.
你不应该来这儿
You shouldn't be here.
你也不应该
Neither should you.
我有任务
I've got a job to do.
这就是你的任务吗
Is that what you're calling this?
杀再多人也换不回你的家人
Killing all these people isn't gonna bring your family back.
我们找到办法了
We found something.
也许还有机会
A chance, maybe.
不要…
Don't.
不要什么
Don't what?
不要给我希望
Don't give me hope.
抱歉没能早点儿给你希望
I'm sorry I couldn't give it to you sooner.
昨晚我做了个梦
♪I had a dream last night♪
梦里我开着飞机
♪I was partying a plane♪
乘客们发着酒疯
♪And all the passengers were drunk and insane♪
别挡道
You're drifting left.
让开点儿 勒保斯基
One side there, Lebowski.
小贱箭 怎么样了
Ratchet, how's it going?
是火箭 别太拽了
It's Rocket.
你也就在地球上算天才
Take it easy. You're only a genius on Earth, pal.
这时空穿梭服不错呀
Time travel suit, not bad.
小心点儿
Hey, hey, hey! Easy! Easy!
我己经很小心了
I'm being very careful.
才没有 你的动作很粗鲁
No, you're being very Hulky.
我真的很小心
I'm being careful.
这些是皮姆粒子
These are Pym Particles, all right?
自从汉克·皮姆消失了以后 就剩这些了
And ever since Hank Pym got snapped out of existence, this is it.
我们只有这些了 再也造不出来了
This is what we have. We're not making any more.
- 斯科特 冷静一下 - 对不起
- Scott, calm down. - Sorry.
我们的量只够每个人往返一次
We've got enough for one round-trip each. That's it.
就这么多 没有再来一次的机会
No do-overs.
而且还有两次测试
Plus two test runs.
不
No
现在只剩一次了
One test run.
好吧 我还没做好准备
All right. I'm not ready for this.
我准备好了
I'm game.
让我来
I'll do it.
克林特 时空穿梭会让你感到有点儿混乱
Clint, now you're gonna feel a little discombobulated from the chronoshift.
别担心
Don't worry about that.
稍等 我有个问题
Wait a second. Let me ask you something.
如果我们能这么做 能穿梭时空
If we can do this, you know...
为什么不直接找到婴儿灭霸
go back in time, why don't we just find baby Thanos?
然后…
You know, and...
首先 这很残忍
First of all, that's horrible.
那可是灭霸
It's Thanos.
而且时间不是这样运作的
And secondly, time doesn't work that way.
改变过去并不能改变未来
Changing the past doesn't change the future.
我们回到过去 在灭霸之前得到原石
Look, we go back, we get the stones before Thanos gets them...
灭霸没有了原石 大功告成
Thanos doesn't have the stones. Problem solved.
- 没错 - 事情不是这样的
- Bingo. - That's not how it works.
我是这么听说的
Well, that's what I heard.
谁告诉你的
Wait, but who? Who told you that?
《星际迷航》《终结者》《时空特警》
Star Trek, Terminator, Timecop...
- 《两世奇人》- 《时空怪客》
- Time After Time. - Quantum Leap.
《时间的褶皱》《时光倒流七十年》
Wrinkle in Time, Somewhere in Time.
《热浴盆时光机》
Hot Tub Time Machine.
《阿比阿弟大冒险》
Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure.
基本上所有和时间旅行有关的电影
Basically, any movie that deals with time travel.
《虎胆龙威》不 那个不算
Die Hard. No, that's not one.
大家都知道的
This is known.
我不知道为什么大家都相信这些
I don't know why everyone believes that,
但这并不正确
but that isn't true.
你想想 如果你回到过去
Think about it. If you travel to the past...
那个过去就变成了你的未来
that past becomes your future...
然后你之前的现在就成了过去
and your former present becomes the past...
这个过去不会因为那个新的未来而改变
which can't now be changed by your new future.
没错
Exactly.
所以《回到未来》是胡编滥造的吗
So Back to the Future is a bunch of bullshit?
好的 克林特
All right, Clint.
倒计时 三 二
We're going in three, two...
一
one.
不
No
库珀
Cooper?
我的耳机呢 莱拉
Where are my headphones? Lila?
- 我没拿 - 莱拉
- I never had them. - Lila?
就是你 你昨天还拿着呢
Yeah, you had them yesterday!
莱拉 莱拉
Lila! Lila!
爸爸
Yeah, Dad?
Dad?
莱拉
Lila!
看着我 你还好吗
Hey, look at me. You okay?
我没事儿
Yeah. Yeah.
成功了
It worked.
我们成功了
时空劫持 头脑风暴会
方法己经成功了
Okay, so the how works.
接下来就是时间和地点的问题了
Now, we gotta figure out the when and the where.
我们几乎每个人应该都曾经接触过
Almost everyone in this room has had an encounter...
六颗无限原石中的某一颗
with at least one of the six Infinity Stones.
你可以把接触过换个说法
Or substitute the word "encounter"...
应该是曾经差点儿被某颗原石搞死
for "damn near been killed" by one of the six Infinity Stones.
我没接触过
Well, I haven't...
根本不知道你们在说些什么
but I don't even know what the hell you're all talking about.
不管怎么说
Regardless, we only have enough Pym Particles
我们的皮姆粒子只够每个人往返一次
for one round-trip each.
历史上这些原石在很多地点出现过
And these stones have been in a lot of different places throughout history.
在我们的历史中
Our history.
没有那么多地点可选
So, not a lot of convenient spots to just drop in, yeah?
所以要选最佳目标
Which means we have to pick our targets.
回答正确
Correct.
那么 我们从以太开始吧
So, let's start with the Aether.
索尔 你知道些什么
Thor, what do you know?
他睡着了吗
Is he asleep?
没有 没有 他己经死了
No, no. I'm pretty sure he's dead.
目标 现实原石
从哪儿说起呢
Uh, where to start? Um...
以太首先就不是个石头
The Aether, firstly, is not a stone.
以前有人把它叫做石头
Someone called it a stone before.
它更像是一种愤怒的烂泥一样的东西
Um, it's more of an angry sludge sort of a thing...
你们最好换个叫法
so someone's gonna need to amend that and stop saying that.
说来话长 关于以太
Here's an interesting story, though, about the Aether.
很多年前我祖父把它藏起来 不让黑暗精灵夺走
My grandfather, many years ago had to hide the stone from the Dark Elves.
好可怕
Ooh. Scary beings.
简 实际上…
So, Jane, actually...
就是她
Oh, there she is.
简是我的旧情人
Yeah, so Jane was an old flame of mine.
有一次她把手伸到了石头里
You know, she stuck her hand inside a rock this one time...
然后以太就进入她体内了
and then the Aether stuck itself inside her...
然后她就变得非常虚弱
and she became very, very sick.
所以我不得不把她带到阿斯加德
And so I had to take her to Asgard,
就是我的故乡 我们试着救她
which is where I'm from, and we had to try and fix her.
那个时候我们在热恋
We were dating at the time, you see...
我得带她见我母亲
and I got to introduce her to my mother...
我母亲死了 然后…
who's dead and, um...
简和我也己经不再见面了
Oh, you know, Jane and I aren't even dating anymore, so...
事情就是这样的
Yes, these things happen, though. You know?
没什么是天长地久的 唯一永恒的…
Nothing lasts forever. The only thing that...
- 先坐下吧 - 我还没说完
- Why don't you come sit down? - I'm not done yet.
生命中唯一永恒的就是生命的无常
The only thing that is permanent in life is impermanence.
太棒了 要吃点儿东西吗
Awesome. Eggs? Breakfast?
不 我要来杯血腥玛丽
No. I'd like a Bloody Mary.
奎尔说他从魔拉格偷走了力量原石
Quill said he stole the Power Stone from Morag.
目标 力量原石
- 魔拉格是谁 - 魔拉格是星球
- Is that a person? - No, Morag's a planet.
奎尔才是人
Quill was a person.
星球 那是在外太空吗
Like a planet? Like in outer space?
看呀
Oh, look.
这只小狗狗无忧无虑乐陶陶
It's like a little puppy, all happy and everything.
你想去太空吗 去不去 小狗狗
Do you wanna go to space? You wanna go to space, puppy?
我带你去太空呀
I'll take you to space.
目标 灵魂原石
灭霸在沃弥尔找到灵魂原石
Thanos found the Soul Stone on Vormir.
沃弥尔是什么
What is Vormir?
宇宙中心的死亡国度
A dominion of death at the very center of celestial existence.
灭霸就是在那里杀了我姐姐
It's where Thanos murdered my sister.
我可不去
Not it.
目标 时间原石
- 那个拿时间原石的 - 斯特兰奇医生
- That Time Stone guy. - Doctor Strange.
他是什么类型的医生
Yeah, what kind of doctor was he?
变戏法的耳鼻喉大夫
Ear-nose-throat meets rabbit-from-hat.
那地方是黄金地段
Nice place in the Village, though.
是在苏利文街吗
Yeah, on Sullivan Street?
是布里克街吧
Mm... Bleecker Street.
等等 他住在纽约吗
Wait, he lived in New York?
不 他住多伦多
No, he lived in Toronto.
对 布里克街和苏利文街那里
Uh, yeah, on Bleecker and Sullivan.
能专心点儿吗
Have you been listening to anything?
各位
Guys.
如果你们挑选一个合适的时间
If you pick the right year,
纽约同时会有三块原石
there are three stones in New York.
真的假的
Shut the front door.
纽约 阿斯加德 魔拉格/沃弥尔
就这么决定了
All right. We have a plan.
六颗原石 三个队伍 一次机会
Six stones, three teams, one shot.
五年前我们所有人一败涂地
Five years ago, we lost. All of us.
我们失去了朋友 我们失去了家人
We lost friends. We lost family.
我们甚至失去了自我
We lost a part of ourselves.
今天我们有机会夺回这一切
Today, we have a chance to take it all back.
我们彼此信任 我们肩负重任
You know your teams. You know your missions.
拿到原石 把它们带回来
Get the stones. Get them back.
每人只有一次往返的机会
One round-trip each.
不能犯错 也不能重来
No mistakes, no do-overs.
我们即将面对的是熟悉的过往
Most of us are going somewhere we know.
但是我们也可能会遇到突发情况
That doesn't mean we should know what to expect.
小心行事 相互照应
Be careful. Look out for each other.
这是我们的命运之战
This is the fight of our lives...
我们必将胜利
and we're gonna win.
不惜一切代价
Whatever it takes.
祝大家好运
Good luck.
他说得真好
He's pretty good at that.
可不是吗
- Right? - All right.
你们都了解了
You heard the man.
启动吧 绿大个儿
Stroke those keys, Jolly Green.
追踪器启动
Trackers engaged.
你得保证给我完好无损地带回来
You promise to bring that back in one piece, right?
好 好 好 我尽力
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay, I'll do my best.
这样的保证也太敷衍了吧
As promises go, that was pretty lame.
一分钟后见
See ya in a minute.
纽
纽   约
我们分头行动
All right, we all have our assignments.
两颗原石在上城区一颗在下城区
Two stones uptown, one stone down.
低调行事 注意时间
Stay low. Keep an eye on the clock.
要不你也砸砸东西 找找感觉
Maybe smash a few things along the way.
我觉得没必要 不过无所谓了
I think it's gratuitous, but whatever.
走那里得小心点 地板刚打过蜡
I'd be careful going that way. We just had the floors waxed.
我来找斯特兰奇医生
Yeah, I'm looking for Doctor Strange.
你大概来早了五年
You're about five years too early.
现在斯特兰奇在二十个街区之外做手术呢
Stephen Strange is currently performing surgery about 20 blocks that way.
你找他干什么
What do you want from him?
就是为了那个
That, actually.
恐怕不行
I'm afraid not.
对不起 但是我也没打算商量
Sorry, but I wasn't asking.
你会后悔的
You don't want to do this.
你说的对 我可能会后悔 但是我需要那块原石
Ah, you're right, I don't. But I need that stone...
我没时间跟你争论
and I don't have time to debate it.
我们从头说起 好吗
Let's start over, shall we?
阿
阿斯
阿斯加
阿斯加德
给您的 小姐
For you, Lady Jane.
你们有裤子吗
Um, so you have anything with pants?
裤子
Pants?
没事儿 这个就很好 谢谢你
Never mind. These will be fine. Thank you.
- 好的小姐 - 那是简
- Yes, milady. - Oh, there's Jane.
好吧
All right.
我们这么干 胖子
Here's the deal, tubby.
你去引诱她 我在后面给她来上这么一针
You're gonna charm her, and I'm gonna poke her with this thing...
把现实原石抽出来以后 我们就溜之大吉
and extract the Reality Stone, and get gone lickety-split.
我去去就回
I'll be right back, okay?
酒窖就在那下面
The wine cellar is just down here.
我父亲以前在那存了大桶的酒
My father used to have this huge barrel of Aakonian ale.
我去后厨看看能不能蹭两杯
I'll see if the scullery has a couple of to-go cups.
难道你还没喝够吗
Hey. Hey! Aren't you drunk enough already?
你可以给洛基送点儿汤去
If you could send Loki some soup.
好的 夫人
Yes, milady.
然后让图书管理员从天文学那边…
And ask our librarians to pull some volumes from the astronomy shelf.
那个时髦的大妈是谁
Who's the fancy broad?
那是我妈
That's my mother.
她今天会被杀死
She dies today.
就是今天吗
Oh, that is today?
我做不到 我做不到
I can't do this. I can't do this.
我不该来这儿 我就不该来
I shouldn't be here. I shouldn't have come.
这是个坏主意
It's a bad idea!
- 过来 - 不不不
- Come here. - No, no, no.
我觉得我快要喘不过来气了
I think I'm having a panic attack.
过来 来这儿
Come here. Right here.
我不该在这里 太糟糕了
I shouldn't be here. This is bad.
你以为只有你失去了亲人吗
You think you're the only one who lost people?
你觉得我们在干什么
What do you think we're doing here?
我失去了我仅有的家人
I lost the only family I ever had.
奎尔 格鲁特 德拉克斯 长触角的小丫头
Quill, Groot, Drax, the chick with the antenna...
他们都不在了
all gone.
我知道你想念你母亲
I get you miss your mom...
但是她也不在了
but she's gone.
再也回不来了
Really gone.
而另一些人是可以被救回来的
And there are plenty of people who are only kind of gone...
需要你的帮助
and you can help them.
所以赶紧把脸上收拾一下
So, is it too much to ask that you brush the crumbs out of your beard...
去和那小妞搭个仙
make schmoopy talk to Pretty Pants...
趁她不注意把无限原石弄出来
and when she's not looking, suck out the Infinity Stone...
帮我把家人救回来
and help me get my family back?
好的
Okay.
你在哭吗
Are you crying?
没有
No.
是的 我觉得我有点儿失控了
Yes. I feel like I'm losing it.
那就控制一下
Get it together!
你没问题的
You can do this.
你行的
好吗
All right?
好 我能行
Yes, I can.
很好
Good.
我能行 我能行
I can do this. I can do this.
我不行
I can't do this.
行了 这位男神 她现在落单了
All right, heartbreaker, she's alone.
我们的机会来了
This is our shot.
索尔 索尔
Thor? Thor!
魔
魔 拉
魔 拉 格
把它放下来 蓝姑娘
All right, bring it down, Blue.
就在那里 放下来
Right on that line. That's it. Down, down.
我们能快点儿吗
Hey, can we hurry it up?
各位 动作利索点儿 我们赶时间
Guys, chop-chop. Come on. We're on the clock.
你们还真是帮忙啊
All that is really helpful.
- 小心点儿 好吗 - 好的
- Take care, okay? - Yeah.
拿了原石就回来 别搞砸了
Get that stone and come back. No messing around.
放心吧
- Hey. - We got this.
- 一切顺利 - 好的
- Let's get it done. - Yes, sir.
回去见
I'll see you back.
你们互相照应着
You guys watch each other's six.
好
Yeah.
己经输入了沃弥尔的坐标
Coordinates for Vormir are laid in.
他们只要不起内讧就行
All they have to do is not fall out.
这可比布达佩斯刺激多了
We're a long way from Budapest.
好吧 那么…
Okay, so, uh...
我们就在这儿等着那个叫奎尔的出现
we just wait around for this Quill guy to show up...
他就会带我们找到力量原石 是吗
and then he leads us to the Power Stone, is that it?
我们埋伏好
Let's take cover.
2014年寻找原石的可不止我们
We're not the only ones in 2014 looking for the stones.
稍等 你说什么
Wait a minute. What are you talking about right now?
还有谁在找这些原石
Who else is looking for these stones?
我父亲
My father...
我姐姐
my sister...
还有我
and me.
还有你吗
And you?
那你现在在哪里
Where are you right now?
不客气
You're welcome.
我可没求你帮我
I didn't ask for your help.
但是你没有我就是不行
And yet, you always need it.
起来吧 父亲要我们回到飞船上
Get up. Father wants us back on the ship.
为什么
Why?
他找到了一颗无限原石
He's found an Infinity Stone.
在哪里
Where?
在一个叫魔拉格的星球上
On a planet called Morag.
父亲的计划终于要启动了
Father's plan is finally in motion.
六分之一而己 星云
One stone isn't six, Nebula.
己经开始了
It's a start.
如果他得到所有的原石
If he gets all of them...
罗南己经发现了力量原石
Ronan's located the Power Stone.
我要派你们去他的飞船上
I'm dispatching you to his ship.
他会很不情愿的
He won't like that.
敢反抗就要他的命
His alternative is death.
罗南的执念会蒙蔽他的双眼
Ronan's obsession clouds his judgment.
我们不会让您失望的 父亲
We will not fail you, Father.
相信你们不会的
No, you won't.
我发誓…
I swear...
您会为我骄傲的
I will make you proud.
我们就在这儿等着那个叫奎尔的出现
...we just wait around for this Quill guy to show up...
他就会带我们找到力量原石 是吗
and then he leads us to the Power Stone, is that it?
我们埋伏好
Let's take cover.
2014年寻找原石的可不止我们
We're not the only ones in 2014 looking for the stones.
那是谁
Who was that?
我不知道 我的头快裂开了
I don't know.
我不知道
My head is splitting. I don't know.
她的感官神经元可能在战斗中损坏了
Her synaptic drive was probably damaged in battle.
把她带上飞船
Bring her to my ship.
快点儿 队长
Better hustle, Cap.
他们己经在收尾了
Things look like they're just about wrapped up here.
收到 我现在就去电梯那里
Got it. I'm approaching the elevator now.
如果还可以的话
If it's all the same to you...
我想喝那杯酒
I'll have that drink now.
行了 让他起来
All right, get him on his feet.
我们耍酷的机会以后还多着呢
We can all stand around posing up a storm later.
还有记得帮我收拾一下
By the way, feel free to clean up.
罗杰斯先生 我差点儿忘了
Mr. Rogers, I almost forgot that that suit...
你那件衣服提臀效果真是不忍直视
did nothing for your ass.
又没人求着你看 托尼
No one asked you to look, Tony.
太夸张了
It's ridiculous.
我觉得挺好 队长
I think you look great, Cap.
我觉得这就是经典的美国翘臀
As far as I'm concerned, that's America's ass.
魔法棒应该交给谁
Who gets the, uh, magic wand?
神盾突击队来了
S.T.R.I.K.E. team's coming to secure it.
交给我们就可以了
We can take that off your hands.
你说了算
By all means.
你们可得小心点儿
Careful with that thing.
除非你们想被洗脑
Yeah, unless you want your mind erased.
那可不是闹着玩儿的
And not in a fun way.
我们肯定会小心的
We promise to be careful.
这帮人是谁
Who are these guys?
他们是神盾局
They are S.H.I.E.L.D.
其实是九头蛇 只不过当时我们谁都不知道
Well, actually Hydra, but we didn't know that yet.
怎么可能 居然不知道
Seriously? You didn't?
这帮人一看就不是好人啊
I mean, they look like bad guys.
你人不大废话还不少啊
You're small, but you're talking loud.
搜索救援由我来指挥
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
这样说话 你们也受得了
I mean, honestly, how do you keep your food down?
闭嘴
Shut up.
该你上场了 小朋友
Ooh. All right, you're up, little buddy.
原石就在那里
There's our stone.
没问题
All right.
把我弹出去
Flick me.
挤挤
Move.
哥们儿 你想什么呢
Hey, hey. Buddy!
你上来电梯非超重不可
What do you think? Maximum occupancy has been reached.
去走楼梯吧 没错
Take the stairs.
别上来了
Yeah. Stop, stop.
讨厌楼梯 讨厌楼梯
"Take the stairs." Hate the stairs.
队长 权杖在电梯里
All right, Cap, I got our scepter in the elevator...
刚过十八层
just passing the 80th floor.
收到
On it.
你去大厅吧
Head to the lobby.
我们大厅见
All right, I'll see you there.
证物己经到手
Evidence secure.
接下来和利斯特博士会合
We're en route to Doctor List.
没有 没有任何阻碍 秘书长先生
No. No hitches at all, Mr. Secretary.
队长 我以为你去指挥搜救了
Captain. I thought you were coordinating search and rescue.
计划有变
Change of plans.
队长
Hey, Cap.
朗姆洛
Rumlow.
我刚接到秘书长的电话
I just got a call from the secretary.
权杖现在由我来接手
I'm gonna be running point on the scepter.
长官 你什么意思
Sir? I don't understand.
有线报说有人要来偷它
We got word there may be an attempt to steal it.
抱歉 队长
Sorry, Cap.
我们不能把权杖给你
We can't give you the scepter.
我得给局长打个电话
I'm gonna have to call the director.
没问题的 相信我
That's okay. Trust me.
九头蛇万岁
Hail Hydra.
楼梯太多了
So many stairs!
拇指姑娘 听得见吗
Thumbelina, do you copy? I've got eyes on the prize.
目标出现 该登场了
It is go time.
己经出动了
Bombs away.
你用了什么香体喷雾吗
Is that Axe Body Spray?
我抽屉里常备
Yeah, I had a can in the desk for emergencies. Relax.
能别废话吗
Can we focus, please?
我要进去了
I'm going inside you...
现在
now.
请问你们要去哪里
Uh, may I ask you where you're going?
去吃午餐 然后会阿斯加德 请问您是
Bit of lunch and then Asgard. I'm sorry, you are...?
亚历山大·皮尔斯
Alexander Pierce.
他就是尼克·弗瑞的头儿
He's the man above the folks behind Nick Fury.
叫我秘书长就行了
My friends call me Mr. Secretary.
那名犯人得交给我来处理
I'm gonna have to ask you to turn that prisoner over to me.
洛基只能由奥丁亲自裁决
Uh, Loki will be answering to Odin himself.
他不能走
No, he's going to answer to us.
奥丁要什么我不管
Odin can have what's left.
那个箱子也得给我
And I'm gonna need that case.
过去七十年它一直属于神盾局
That's been S.H.I.E.L.D. property for over 70 years.
把箱子交出来 史塔克
Hand over the case, Stark.
快点儿动手 鼠小弟
All right, move it, Stuart Little.
情况有点儿失控了
Things are getting dicey out here. Let's go.
我不想争论现在谁说了算
I'm not gonna argue who's got the higher authority here...
你确定你不会死
You promise me you won't die?
就一点儿心律失常而己
We're only giving me a mild cardiac dysrhythmia.
你确定只有一点儿吗
That doesn't sound mild.
把箱子给我
I need the case.
我知道你的权力不小 但是法律上…
I know you got a lot of pull, I'm just saying, jurisdiction...
别废话 把箱子给我
Okay, then give me the case.
法律上他是…
Well, jurisdiction...
给我松手 给我松手
Hand it over.
快动手
Do it, Lang!
把你的手拿开
Get your hands off me.
快没时间了 拔掉插头
Window's closing. Pull my pin.
要拔了
Here goes!
史塔克
- Stark? - Stark?
他在抽搐 他需要透气
He's convulsing. Give him air!
叫急救
- Medic! - Medic!
呼叫急救 有人需要帮助
Give these guys some help.
醒醒
Speak to me.
史塔克 是你胸前的机器吗
Stark, is it your chest machine?
深呼吸 深呼吸
Breathe, breathe.
干得好 我们在小巷见
Good job. Meet me in the alley.
我先吃口东西
I'm gonna grab a quick slice.
不要 楼梯
No stairs!
史塔克 保持清醒 保持清醒
Uh... Come on, Stark, stay with us.
我要试试看
I'm going to try something. Okay?
我也不知道行不行
I have no idea if it's going to work.
行了
Yes!
这还真行
Oh, that worked a treat.
这太疯狂了
Dude, that was so crazy.
我也没想到
I had no idea if that was gonna work.
- 箱子呢 - 箱子
- The case. - The case is, uh...
箱子去哪儿了 洛基呢
Where's the case? Where's Loki?
洛基
Loki!
结果不应该是这样的 对不对
That wasn't supposed to happen, was it?
我们搞砸了
Oh, we blew it.
洛基
Loki?
托尼 怎么回事儿
Tony, what's going on?
你们拿到魔方了吧
Tell me you found that Cube.
这也太扯了吧
Oh, you gotta be shitting me.
我发现洛基了 在十四楼
I have eyes on Loki. 14th floor.
我不是洛基
I'm not Loki...
而且我也不想伤害你
and I don't wanna hurt you.
我可以打一整天
I can do this all day.
行了 我知道 我知道
Yeah, I know. I know.
你怎么会有这个
Where did you get this?
巴基…还…活着
Bucky is alive.
你说什么
What?
这还真是美国翘臀
That is America's ass.
求求你了 抱歉
Please, please.
我帮不了你 布鲁斯
I'm sorry, I can't help you, Bruce.
如果我把时间原石交给你 去拯救你们的现实
If I give up the Time Stone
我们的现实就会危在旦夕
to help your reality, I'm dooming my own.
恕我直言 科学理论应该不是这样的
With all due respect, all right. I'm not sure the science really supports that.
无限原石缔造了你们所感受到的时间流
The Infinity Stones create what you experience as the flow of time.
少了一颗原石就意味着分流
Remove one of the stones and that flow splits.
这样可能对你们的现实有帮助
Now, this may benefit your reality...
但是我这里的情况可就不一定了
but my new one, not so much.
在这个新的现实分支里
In this new branch reality...
失去了对抗黑暗力量的主要武器
without our chief weapon against the forces of darkness...
我们的世界将危在旦夕
our world would be overrun.
人们会遭受灭顶之灾
Millions will suffer.
所以告诉我 博士
So, tell me, Doctor.
你的科学理论能阻止这一切吗
Can your science prevent all that?
不能
No...
但可以消除这一切
but we can erase it.
因为一旦我们用完了这些原石
Because once we're done with the stones...
我们会在最初的时间点将其物归原主
we can return each one to its own timeline at the moment it was taken.
所以从时空角度来说
So, chronologically...
在原来的现实中…
in that reality...
这些原石从来就没有离开过
it never left.
但是你遗漏了一个最重要的问题
Yes, but you're leaving out the most important part.
想要物归原主 你们必须活下来
In order to return the stones, you have to survive.
我们会的 我会的 我保证
We will. I will. I promise.
我不能因为一个保证就冒这个险
I can't risk this reality on a promise.
至上尊者的职责就是守护时间原石
It's the duty of the Sorcerer Supreme to protect the Time Stone.
那为什么斯特兰奇把它交出去了
Then why the hell did Strange give it away?
你说什么
What did you say?
斯特兰奇 他把时间原石交出去了 交给了灭霸
Strange. He gave it away. He gave it to Thanos.
- 自愿的吗 - 是的
- Willingly? - Yes.
- 为什么 - 我也不知道
Why? I have no idea.
或许他错了
Maybe he made a mistake.
或许是我错了
Or I did.
斯特兰奇应该是我们中最出色的
Strange is meant to be the best of us.
所以他这么做一定有原因
So, he must've done it for a reason.
恐怕你是对的
I fear you might be right.
谢谢你
Thank you.
全靠你了 布鲁斯
I'm counting on you, Bruce.
我们都靠你了
We all are.
再检查一遍
Run diagnostics.
给我看看她的记忆文件
Show me her memory file.
大人 记忆文件有些混乱
Sire, the file appears entangled.
这段记忆存在 但不是她的
It was a memory, but not hers.
有另一个意识在共享她的神经网络
There's another consciousness sharing her network.
另一个星云
Another Nebula.
不可能
Impossible.
这个复制品的时间戳
This duplicate carries a time stamp...
来自九年以后的未来
from nine years in the future.
另一个星云在哪里
Where is this other Nebula?
在我们的星系里 魔拉格那里
In our solar system on Morag.
你能接入她的记忆吗
Can you access her?
可以 两个意识是相连的
Yes, the two are linked.
在这个复制品的记忆里 搜索无限原石
Search the duplicate's memories for Infinity Stones.
历史中这些原石在很多地点出现过
And these stones have been in a lot of different places throughout history.
在我们的历史中
Our history.
没有那么多地点可选
So, not a lot of convenient spots to just drop in.
所以要选最佳目标
Which means we have to pick our targets.
- 回答正确 - 暂停影像
- Correct. - Freeze image.
地球人
Terrans.
复仇者
Avengers.
一群无名鼠辈
Unruly wretches.
那是什么
What's that reflection?
把图像放大
Amplify this, Maw.
我不明白
I don't understand.
有两个星云
Two Nebulas.
不 是同一个星云
No. The same Nebula...
来自两个不同的时间
from two different times.
立刻启航魔拉格
Set course for Morag.
继续扫描复制品的记忆
And scan the duplicate's memories.
我要看所有的一切
I wanna see everything.
亲爱的 等会儿见
My ladies, I'll see you after.
咱们一会儿再说吧
I'll see you after. Go on ahead.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
鬼鬼祟祟的事还是让你弟弟来吧
You're better off leaving the sneaking to your brother.
我没有鬼鬼祟祟 我正要去散步而己
No, I wasn't sneaking. I was just going for a walk.
你这是什么打扮
What are you wearing?
我一直是这个打扮 这是我最喜欢的
I always wear this. It's one of my favorites.
你的眼睛怎么了
What's wrong with your eye?
我的眼睛 你还记得哈罗金之战吗
Remember the, uh, Battle of Harokin...
我被剑砍中脸了
when I got hit in the face with the broadsword?
你不是我认识的索尔 对不对
You're not the Thor I know at all, are you?
我是
Yes, I am.
未来让你受了很多苦吧
The future hasn't been kind to you, has it?
我可没说我来自未来
I didn't say I was from the future.
我是女巫抚养长大的
I was raised by witches, boy.
我看到的可不止表面 你知道的
I see with more than eyes, you know that.
我真的是来自未来的
Yeah, I'm totally from the future.
是的 亲爱的
Yes, you are, honey.
我真的想和你说说话
I really need to talk to you.
馒慢说
We can talk.
他的头在这边
His head was over there...
他的身体在那边
and his body over there...
可是这又有什么意义一切都太晚了
I mean, what was the point? I was too late.
我站在那儿
I was just standing there.
就是个拿着斧子的蠢货
Some idiot with an axe.
你一点儿都不蠢
Now, you're no idiot.
你不是来这里了吗
You're here, aren't you?
来向阿斯加德最睿智的人求助
Seeking counsel from the wisest person in Asgard.
是的
I am. Yes.
蠢货算不上
Idiot, no.
但失败是肯定的
A failure? Absolutely.
这可有点儿伤人
That's a little bit harsh.
你知道失败意味着什么吗
Do you know what that makes you?
意味着你和其他人一样
Just like everyone else.
但是我应该和其他人不一样
I'm not supposed to be like everyone else, am I?
每个人在寻找自我的过程中都会经历失败 索尔
Everyone fails at who they're supposed to be, Thor.
衡量一个人一个英雄的标准是
The measure of a person, of a hero...
他们如何最终成就自我
is how well they succeed at being who they are.
我真的很想念您 妈妈
I've really missed you, Mom.
索尔 我拿到啦
Thor! I got it!
抓住那只兔子
Get that rabbit!
妈妈 我有些事必须要告诉你
Mom, I have to tell you something.
不 儿子 不需要
No, son, you don't.
你要拯救的是你的未来 不是我的
You're here to repair your future, not mine.
这和你的未来有关
This is about your future.
和我没关系
Uh, it's none of my business.
你好
Hi.
你肯定是他母亲
You must be Mom.
我得手了 我们得赶紧撤
I got the thing. Come on. We gotta move.
真想陪您多待一会
Oh, I wish we had more time.
不 这就足够了
No, this was a gift.
快去成就你自己吧
Now you go and be the man you're meant to be.
我爱你 妈妈
I love you, Mom.
我也爱你
I love you.
多吃点儿素
And eat a salad.
我们赶紧撤
Come on, we gotta go.
- 再见 - 三
- Goodbye. - Three...
- 二… - 等等
- Two... - No, wait!
又怎么了
What am I looking at?
有时候确实需要点儿时间
Oh, sometimes it takes a second.
我仍然配得上这个
I'm still worthy.
真是够了
Oh, boy.
- 再见 妈妈 - 再见
- Goodbye, Mom. - Goodbye.
嘿哟
♪Hail Hail♪
你在想什么 你在做什么
♪What's the matter with your mind and your sighing♪
嘿哟
♪Hail Hail♪
你的想法一点儿没错
♪Nothin's a matter♪
宝贝儿 去寻找它
♪With your head baby find it♪
去寻找吧
♪Come on and find it♪
它是你的 宝贝儿
♪Hell with it baby♪
你如此完美 你令我沉醉
♪Cause you're fine and you're mine♪
你光芒万丈
♪And you look so divine♪
来得到你的爱
♪Come and get you love♪
他是个傻子吧
So, he's an idiot?
没错
Yeah.
那是什么
What's that?
盗贼的工具
The tool of a thief.
是不是该有尖刺冒出来
This is the part where spikes come out...
上面挂着骷髅什么的
with skeletons on the end of them and everything.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
像力量原石神庙之类的地方
When you break into a place called "The Temple of the Power Stone"...
总会有点儿陷阱吧
there's gonna be a bunch of booby traps.
好吧 我们继续
- Oh, my God. - Okay. All right. Go ahead.
我以前不是这样的
I wasn't always like this.
我也不是
Me either.
但是我们别无选择 对不对
But we work with what we got, right?
同步开始
Let's sync up.
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
你杀害了无数生命
You murdered trillions!
你们应该为之感恩
You should be grateful.
原石在哪里
Where are the stones?
不在了 一切归为尘埃
Gone. Reduced to atoms.
你两天前才刚刚用过
You used them two days ago!
我使用原石摧毁了原石
I used the stones to destroy the stones.
这几乎要了我的命
It nearly killed me.
但我的使命完成了
But the work is done.
注定如此
It always will be.
我就是…天命
I am inevitable.
你对他们做了什么
What did you do to them?
什么都没做
Nothing.
目前为止
Yet.
他们不是要阻止此时此刻我要做的事情
They're not trying to stop something I'm going to do in our time.
他们是想逆转彼时彼刻我己经完成的事情
They're trying to undo something I've already done in theirs.
原石…
The stones.
我收集齐了
I found them all.
我赢了
I won.
宇宙的天平达到了平衡
Tipped the cosmic scales to balance.
这就是您的未来
This is your future.
这就是我的宿命
It's my destiny.
我父亲什么都干得出来
My father is many things.
但他从不说谎
A liar is not one of them.
谢谢你 女儿
Thank you, daughter.
可能我对你太苛刻了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly.
我完成了我的宿命
And that is destiny fulfilled.
大人 您的女儿…
Sire...your daughter...
不 不要
No!
是个叛徒
...is a traitor.
那不是我 我不可能
That's not me. It's not, I could never...
我永远不会背叛您
I would never betray you. Never. Never.
我知道
I know.
现在是证明你自己的时候了
And you'll have the chance to prove it.
不
No!
他发现了
He knows!
巴顿 巴顿 你在吗
Barton! Barton, come in.
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff!
我们有麻烦了
Come in, we have a problem.
快回答
Come on!
灭霸发现了
Thanos knows.
灭霸…
Thanos...
队长
Cap.
抱歉 我们有麻烦了
Sorry, buddy, we got a problem.
是有点儿麻烦
Yeah, we do.
我们现在该怎么办
Well, what are we gonna do now?
让我缓缓 史蒂夫
You know what? Give me a break, Steve.
我刚被浩克砸了头
I just got hit in the head with the Hulk.
你说过我们只有一次机会
You said that we had one shot.
这就是我们唯一的机会
This was our shot.
我们用了 就没得用了 凑不齐就白费
We shot it. It's shot. Six stones or nothing.
- 凑不齐就白费 - 你在重复自己的话
- It was six stones or nothing. - You're repeating yourself,
你知道吗 你在重复你自己
you know that? You're repeating yourself.
重复自己的是你
You're repeating yourself. You're repeating yourself.
老兄 有完没完
Dude. Come on!
你根本不想搞时空劫持
No. You never wanted a time heist.
你根本不赞成
You weren't on board with the time heist.
我没拿住 我毁了一切
- I dropped the ball. - You ruined the time heist.
- 都怪我吗 - 是啊
- Is that what I did? - Yeah.
还有什么办法能搞到宇宙魔方吗
Are there any other options with the Tesseract?
没有了 没其他办法了
No, no, no, there's no other options.
没有再来一次的机会
There's no do-overs.
哪儿也去不了 我们每个人只有一管粒子
We're not going anywhere else. We have one particle left.
一管
Each.
就这么多 明白吗
That's it. All right? We use that...
我们要是用了 再见 你们别想回家了
bye-bye, you're not going home.
可是如果我们不尝试一下
Yeah, well, if we don't try...
那其他人也一样回不了家
then no one else is going home, either.
我知道了
I got it.
还有个办法 既能再次得到宇宙魔方
There's another way to retake the Tesseract
又能补充新的粒子
and acquire new particles.
在回忆的小路上多走几步
Little stroll down memory lane.
新泽西州的军事基地
Military installation, Garden State.
当时两样东西都在那儿吗
When were they both there?
有段时间是 我记得好像很清楚
They were there at a time... I have a vaguely exact idea.
- 好像很清楚 - 你们说什么呢
- How vague? - What are you talking about?
我们要去哪儿
Where are we going?
我肯定它们在那儿
I know for a fact they were there.
谁啊 我们要干吗
Who's they? What are we doing?
我知道我为什么知道
And I know how I know.
二位 你们在说什么
Guys, what is it?
看来得即兴发挥一下了
Looks like we're improvising.
- 好的 - 即兴发挥什么
- Great. - What are we improvising?
斯科特 把这个带回去
Scott, get this back to the compound.
准备出发
Suit up.
新泽西有什么
What's in New Jersey?
- 零四 - 零四
0-4. 0-4.
- 零七 - 零七
- Uh, 0-7. - 0-7.
你们听见了吗 一九七零
Excuse me. 1-9-7-0.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
队长 队长
Cap? Captain?
史蒂夫 不好意思
Steve? Sorry.
美国…罗杰斯
America. Rogers.
如果你们这么做了
Look, if you do this...
结果失败了 你们就回不来了
and it doesn't work, you're not coming back.
谢谢你的鼓励 小蚂蚁
Thanks for the pep talk, pissant.
你相信我吗
You trust me?
我相信
I do.
听你号令
Your call.
出发
Here we go.
新
新 泽
新 泽 西
无需多言
哥们儿 要爱情 不要战争
Hey, man! Make love, not war.
美军基地
美国队长的诞生地
你肯定不是在这儿出生的 对吧
Clearly you weren't actually born here, right?
创造我的想法是在这诞生的
The idea of me was.
好吧 假设你是神盾局
Right. Well, imagine you're S.H.I.E.L.D...
要搞个跟纳粹一样的情报组织
running a quasi-fascistic intelligence organization...
你会把它藏在什么地方
where do you hide it?
就放在明处
In plain sight.
祝你任务顺利 队长
Good luck on your mission, Captain.
祝你项目顺利 博士
Good luck on your project, Doctor.
你是新来的吗
You new here?
其实不完全是
Not exactly.
快啊 该死
Come on, you bastard.
粒子检测 伽马特征 不匹配
目标匹配
找到了
Gotcha.
重返赛场啦
Back in the game.
阿尼姆 你在这儿吗
Arnim, you in there?
阿尼姆
Arnim?
门在这边 朋友
The door is this way, pal.
好
Oh, yeah.
我在找索拉博士 你看见他了吗
Looking for Doctor Zola, have you seen him?
索拉博士 没看见 这儿连个人影儿都没有
Yeah, Doctor Zola. No, I haven't seen a soul.
不好意思
Pardon me.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
不 先生 我是…
No, sir. Uh...
我是麻省理工来的访客
I'm a visitor from MIT.
麻省理工啊
Oh. MIT.
你叫什么
Got a name?
霍华德
Howard.
- 名字挺好记的 - 霍华德
- That'll be easy to remember. - Howard...
波兹
Potts.
我是霍华德·史塔克
Well, I'm Howard Stark.
你好
Hi.
来握个手 别紧张
Shake that, don't pull it.
好
Yeah.
你看上去脸色不太好啊 波兹
You look a little green around the gills, there, Potts.
我没事儿 就是有点儿累
I'm fine. Just long hours.
想出去呼吸一下新鲜空气吗
You wanna get some air?
- 怎么样 波兹 - 好
- Hello, Potts. - Yeah.
- 那再好不过了 - 那边走
- That'd be swell. - That way.
好的
Okay.
别忘了你的箱子
Need your briefcase?
你不是披头族吧 波兹
You're not one of those beatniks, are you, Potts?
- 你好 - 皮姆博士
- Hello? -  Doctor Pym?
你拨的号码没错 是我
That would be the number that you called, yes.
我是负责运输的史蒂文斯队长
This is Captain Stevens from shipping.
有您的包裹
We have a package for you.
拿上来吧
Oh, bring it up.
问题就是我拿不上去
That's the thing, sir, we can't.
我很困惑 这不是你们该做的吗
I'm confused. I thought that was your job.
是的 只是…
Well, it's just...
先生 这个箱子在发光
Sir, the box is glowing...
说老实话 我们的邮递员有点儿不敢碰
and to be honest, some of our mail guys aren't feeling that great.
他们没打开吧
They didn't open it, did they?
他们打开了 你最好赶紧下来
Uh, yeah, they did. You better get down here.
给我让开
Excuse me! Out of the way!
皮姆粒子 请勿触碰
鲜花和酸菜罐头 今晚有约会吗
So, flowers and sauerkraut. You got a big date tonight?
我妻子怀孕了
Uh, my wife's expecting.
而且我最近加班太多了
And too much time at the office.
恭喜你啊
Congratulations.
- 谢谢 帮我拿一下好吗 - 没问题
- Thanks. Hold this, will ya? - Yeah, sure.
- 她怀孕多长时间了 - 我也不知道
- How far along is she? - Uh, I don't know.
反正她现在受不了我吃饭出声
She's at the point where she can't stand the sound of my chewing.
没准儿我又得在后厨吃饭了
I guess I'll be eating dinner in the pantry again.
我有个女儿
I have a little girl.
女儿很好啊
A girl would be nice.
变成和我一模一样的几率会低一些
Less of a chance she'd turn out exactly like me.
和你一样有什么问题吗
What'd be so awful about that?
我总是把个人爱好放在集体利益之上
Let's just say that the greater good has rarely outweighed my own self-interest.
你从来没有见过这两个人吗
And you've never seen these two men before?
没有 我就是觉得这两个人很可疑
No, I've got an eye for this. The two of them looked fishy.
你能描述他们的长相吗
Can you describe them?
其中一个留着嬉皮士的胡子
One of them had a hippie beard.
像比吉斯还是蒙哥杰瑞
Hippie. Like Bee Gees or Mungo Jerry?
绝对像蒙哥杰瑞
Definitely Mungo Jerry.
所有人赶往六层 有人非法入侵
I need every available MP to sublevel six. We have a potential breach.
玛格丽特·卡特 局长
好 让他们进来吧
I said bring them in.
他们在努力 长官
They're trying, ma'am, but Braddock's unit
布拉德克的小队遭遇了雷电风暴
has been stopped by lightning strikes.
该死 我以后会看天气预报
Oh, for the love of...I'll look at the weather projections.
给布拉德克打电话 告诉他找地方躲一下
希望他不至于蠢到淋雨 遵命长官
就这样
天啊 中士
您请讲 你能呼叫空军吗
布拉德克需要立刻支援 现在吗
我们看到的根本不是什么雷电风暴
It's not lightning strikes we're looking at.
那么你起好名字了吗
So, where you at with names?
如果是男孩 我妻子想叫他艾蒙佐
Well, if it's a boy, my wife likes Elmonzo.
你可以不用着急做决定 再想想
Huh. Might wanna let that stew awhile. You got time.
我想问问你
Let me ask you a question.
当你的孩子出生的时候
When your kid was born, were you nervous?
你紧张吗 超级紧张
Wildly.
- 是的 - 你觉得自己准备好了吗
- Yeah. - Did you feel qualified?
你知道如何成功地应付吗
Like you had any idea
how to successfully operate that thing?
我还真从头到尾仔细想了一遍
I literally pieced it together as I went along.
我想了我父亲都做过什么
I thought about what my dad did.
我父亲 没有他用皮带解决不了的麻烦
My old man, he never met a problem he couldn't solve with a belt.
我觉得我父亲对我也挺苛刻
I thought my dad was tough on me.
但是现在回想起来
And now, looking back on it,
我想到的都是些美好的事儿
I just remember the good stuff.
你知道吗 他说的话字字珠矶
You know? He did drop the odd pearl.
是吗 比如说
Yeah? Like what?
寸金难买寸光阴
"No amount of money ever bought a second of time."
这家伙挺聪明
Smart guy.
他尽力了
He did his best.
我跟你说 孩子虽然还没出生
I'll tell you, that kid's not even here yet
但为了他我什么都愿意做
and there's nothing I wouldn't do for him.
很高兴见到你 波兹
Good to meet you, Potts.
霍华德
Howard...
一切都会好的
everything's gonna be all right.
谢谢您做的一切
Thank you...for everything...
为这个国家做的一切
you've done for this country.
贾维斯
Jarvis.
我们以前见过那个人吗
Have we ever met that guy?
您见过的人太多了 先生
You meet a lot of people, sir.
感觉特别熟悉
Seems very familiar.
胡子有点儿怪
Weird beard.
你太弱了
You're weak.
我就是你
I'm you.
你可以阻止这一切
You could stop this.
你知道你想阻止的
You know you want to.
你没看见未来发生了什么吗
Did you see what happens in the future?
灭霸找到了灵魂原石
Thanos finds the Soul Stone.
你想知道他是怎么找到的吗
You wanna know how he does that?
你想知道他对你做了什么吗
You wanna know what he does to you?
够了
That's enough.
你让我恶心
You disgust me.
但是你还不是完全没用
But that doesn't mean you're useless.
我看起来怎么样
How do I look?
沃
沃 弥
沃 弥 尔
要不是任务紧迫
Under different circumstances...
这地方还真值得转转
this would be totally awesome.
浣熊他们肯定不用爬山
I bet the raccoon didn't have to climb a mountain.
严格的说 它不是浣熊
Technically he's not a raccoon, you know?
无所谓了 反正它吃垃圾
Oh, whatever. He eats garbage.
欢迎
Welcome.
娜塔莎 伊万之女
Natasha. Daughter of Ivan.
克林特 艾迪斯之子
Clint. Son of Edith.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是引领所有人通往灵魂原石的向导
Consider me a guide to you and to all who seek the Soul Stone.
正好
Oh, good.
你告诉我们位置 我们去就是了
You tell us where it is, then we'll be on our way.
要是这么简单就好了
If only it were that easy.
你们所追寻的近在眼前
What you seek lies in front of you.
与你们的恐惧相伴
As does what you fear.
原石在下面
The stone's down there.
对于你
For one of you.
或是对于他
For the other...
想得到原石必须失去至爱
In order to take the stone, syou must lose that which you love.
这是永恒的交易
An everlasting exchange.
以魂换魂
A soul for a soul.
怎么样了
How's it going?
天啊
Jesus.
没准全都是他胡扯的
Maybe he's making this shit up.
不 我觉得不是
No. I don't think so.
就因为他知道你父亲的名字
Why? 'Cause he knows your daddy's name?
连我自己都不知道
I didn't.
灭霸从这里拿走了原石
Thanos left here with the stone...
没带他的女儿离开
without his daughter.
这可不是巧合
That's not a coincidence.
对
Yeah.
不惜一切代价
Whatever it takes.
如果我们得不到原石
If we don't get that stone...
亿万人就不可能活过来
billions of people stay dead.
我知道
Yeah.
我觉得我们都知道该谁去
Then I guess we both know who it's gotta be.
我们都知道
I guess we do.
我觉得咱俩的人选可能不太一样 娜塔莎
I'm starting to think we mean different people here, Natasha.
过去五年里 我的目标只有一个
For the last five years, I've been trying to do one thing.
来到这里 而这一切就是为了
Get to right here.
把所有人带回来
That's all it's been about. Bringing everybody back.
别跟我说什么漂亮话 娜塔莎
No, don't you get all decent on me now.
你以为我想这么做吗
What, you think I wanna do it?
我是在拯救你的性命 笨蛋
I'm trying to save your life, you idiot.
我真的不想让你这么做
Yeah, well, I don't want you to. How's that?
娜塔莎 你知道我的所作所为
Natasha, you know what I've done.
你知道我变成了什么
You know what I've become.
我从来不用过错来评判一个人
Oh, I don't judge people on their worst mistakes.
也许你应该这样做
Maybe you should.
你自己都做不到
You didn't.
我真是拿你没办法
You're a pain in my ass, you know that?
好吧
Okay.
你赢了
You win.
告诉家人我爱他们
Tell my family I love 'em.
你自己去告诉他们
You tell 'em yourself.
该死
Damn you.
等等
Wait.
放开我吧
Let me go.
不行
No.
求你了 不
No. Please, no.
没事儿的
It's okay.
不要
Please.
不
No!
拿到所有原石了吗
Did we get 'em all?
我们居然成功了
Are you telling me this actually worked?
克林特 娜塔莎呢
Clint, where's Nat?
她有家人吗
Do we know if she had family?
也就是我们了吧
Yeah. Us.
什么
What?
- 你们干什么 - 我问了个问题而己
- What are you doing? - Just asked him a question.
你说的好像她己经死了一样
Yeah, no, you're acting like she's dead.
为什么要当作她死了
Why are we acting like she's dead?
我们有原石 对不对
We have the stones, right?
只要我们有这些原石 我们就能把她带回来
As long as we have the stones...
是不是啊 所以别再废话了
Cap, we can bring her back. Isn't that right?
我们可是复仇者 打起精神来
So, stop this shit. We're the Avengers. Get it together.
她回不来了
Can't get her back.
他说什么
What's he...? What?
无法逆转
It can't be undone.
做不到的
It can't.
不好意思 我没有冒犯的意思
Look, I'm sorry, no offense,
你只是个普通的地球人
but you're a very earthly being, okay?
我说的是宇宙魔法
And we're talking about space magic.
说做不到太绝对了吧
And "can't" seems very definitive. Don't you think?
我知道这件事儿我没有发言权
Yeah, look, I know that I'm way outside my pay grade here.
但是她仍然是回不来的
But she still isn't here, is she?
我觉得不是
No, that's my point.
这一切没法挽回的
It can't be undone.
至少那个飘着的红色家伙是这么说的
Or that's at least what the red, floating guy had to say.
也许你可以去跟他聊聊啊
Maybe you wanna go talk to him, okay?
拿上你的锤子飞过去找他啊
Go grab your hammer and you go fly and you talk to him.
本来该是我的
It was supposed to be me.
她为了这块该死的原石牺牲了自己
She sacrificed her life for that goddamn stone.
这是她用命换来的
She bet her life on it.
她回不来了
She's not coming back.
我们不能辜负这一切
We have to make it worth it.
一定不能辜负
We have to.
一定不会
We will.
手套准备好了
All right, the glove's ready.
问题是谁来打那个要命的响指呢
Question is, who's gonna snap their freakin' fingers?
- 我来 - 你说什么
- I'll do it. - Excuse me?
没问题的
It's okay.
住手 住手 等等
Stop, stop. Slow down.
索尔 别急
Thor. Just wait.
我们还没决定谁来戴这个手套呢
We haven't decided who's gonna put that on yet.
说什么 难道我们就坐在这干等着吗
I'm sorry. What, we're all just sitting around waiting for the right opportunity?
我们应该至少讨论一下
We should at least discuss it.
坐在这干瞪眼可没法把所有人救回来
Look, sitting here staring at the thing is not gonna bring everybody back.
我是最强的复仇者
I'm the strongest Avenger, okay?
所以这个责任必须落在我身上
So, this responsibility falls upon me.
这是我的使命
- Normally, you're right. - It's my duty.
- 你说的没错 - 但和这些没关系
- It's not about that. - It's not that.
住手 让我来
Hey, buddy... Stop it! Just let me.
让我来啊
Just let me do it.
让我做点儿好事吧 做点儿正确的事
Just let me do something good. Something right.
这个手套会聚集惊天动地的能量
Look, it's not just the fact that that glove is channeling enough energy
而且我告诉你
to light up a continent.
你的状态根本不行
I'm telling you. You're in no condition.
你以为我的血液里流淌的是什么
What do you think is coursing through my veins right now?
奶酪酱
Cheez Whiz?
是闪电啊 对 闪电
Lightning.
闪电也帮不了你 哥们儿
Yeah. Lightning. Lightning won't help you, pal.
还是得我来
It's gotta be me.
你们也看见灭霸的下场了
You saw what those stones did to Thanos.
这些原石几乎要了他的命
They almost killed him.
你们都扛不住的
None of you could survive.
那为什么你能扛得住
How do we know you will?
我不确定
We don't.
可这石头释放的主要是伽马射线
But the radiation's mostly gamma.
就好像…
It's like...
这就是我存在的意义
I was made for this.
准备好了
Good to go, yeah?
来吧
Let's do it.
记住 灭霸五年前湮灭的所有人
Okay, remember, everyone Thanos snapped away five years ago...
你要把他们带回到现在 就是今天
you're just bringing them back to now, today.
千万不要改变过去五年里的任何事儿
Don't change anything from the last five years.
你放心
Got it.
星期五 启动防御程序
Friday, do me a favor and activate Barn Door Protocol, will ya?
是的 老板
Yes, boss.
所有人都回来吧
Everybody comes home.
摘下来 快摘下来
Take it off! Take it off!
等等 布鲁斯 你还好吗
No, wait. Bruce, are you okay?
说句话 班纳
Talk to me, Banner.
我没事儿 我没事儿
I'm okay.
通道开启 时间起点 2014年
布鲁斯
Bruce!
不要动他
Don't move him.
- 成功了吗 - 不确定 没事儿了
- Did it work? - We're not sure. It's okay.
劳拉 来电
亲爱的
Honey.
克林特
Clint?
亲爱的
Honey.
各位
Guys...
我觉得成功了
I think it worked.
我喘不上气了 喘不上气了
I can't breathe! I can't breathe!
战甲解除 战甲解除
Canopy, canopy, canopy.
罗德 火箭 快跑
Rhodey, Rocket, get out of here.
让我出去
Let me up! Let me up!
快点儿
Come on!
罗德
Rhodey!
呼叫救援 有人听到吗
Mayday, Mayday! Does anybody copy?
我们在底层 这里被淹了
We're on the lower level. It's flooding!
什么
What? What?
我们快被淹死了 有人收到吗 救命
We are drowning! Does anybody copy? Mayday!
等等 我在这儿
Wait! I'm here!
我在这儿 你们能听到吗
I'm here. Can you hear me?
队长
Cap?
好吧
Okay.
女儿
Daughter.
父亲
Yes, Father.
这就是未来吗
So, this is the future.
干得漂亮
Well done.
谢谢您 父亲
Thank you, Father.
他们一点儿都没有怀疑
They suspected nothing.
因为他们自以为是
The arrogant never do.
去吧
Go.
找到原石 给我带回来
Find the stones, bring them to me.
您要做什么
What will you do?
等待
Wait.
告诉我
Tell me something.
在未来
In the future...
你我之间怎么样了
what happens to you and me?
我想要杀了你
I try to kill you.
试了许多次
Several times.
但是最终…
But eventually...
我们成了朋友
we become friends.
成了真正的姐妹
We become sisters.
来吧
Come on.
我们可以阻止他
We can stop him.
哥们儿 醒醒
Come on, buddy, wake up!
好样的
That's my man.
你要是再弄丢了 我就不给你了
You lose this again, I'm keeping it.
怎么回事儿
What happened?
你玩弄时间 时间就会玩弄你
You mess with time, it tends to mess back.
你会明白的
You'll see.
他在做什么
What's he been doing?
什么都没做
Absolutely nothing.
原石在哪里
Where are the stones?
在这下面某个地方
Somewhere under all this.
总之他还没得手
All I know is he doesn't have 'em.
那就一定别让他拿到
So, we keep it that way.
你知道这是个陷阱吧
You know it's a trap, right?
知道 我不在乎
Yeah. I don't much care.
好
Good.
只要我们同心协力
Just as long as we're all in agreement.
这一次让我们彻底了结他
Let's kill him properly this time.
你们不甘心接受失败
You could not live with your own failure.
结果又怎么样
Where did that bring you?
还是要面对我
Back to me.
我以为消灭掉半数生命
I thought by eliminating half of life...
另外一半就能繁荣下去
the other half would thrive.
但是你们向我证明…
But you've shown me...
那是不可能的
that's impossible.
只要仍然有人牵挂过去
And as long as there are those that remember what was...
就永远不可能接受未来
there will always be those that are unable to accept what can be.
就一定会反抗
They will resist.
没错 我们就是这么固执
Yep, we're all kinds of stubborn.
谢谢你们
I'm thankful.
因为现在…我知道我必须做什么了
Because now...I know what I must do.
我要让这个宇宙化为原子尘埃
I will shred this universe down to its last atom.
然后 用你们帮我找到的原石
And then with the stones you've collected for me...
创造一个新的宇宙
create a new one...
那里的生命没有对失去的怨恨
teeming with life that knows not what it has lost...
只有对给予的感恩
but only what it has been given.
一个懂得感恩的宇宙
A grateful universe.
血债累累的宇宙
Born out of blood.
他们无从得知
They'll never know it.
因为你们活不到那个时候
Because you won't be alive to tell them.
来世再见了
See you on the other side, man.
坚持住 我来了
Hang on! I'm coming!
好
Yeah!
是你啊
I know you.
父亲 我找到原石了
Father, I have the stones.
什么
What?
住手
Stop.
你叛变了
You're betraying us?
你不必这样做
You don't have to do this.
我必须这样做
I am this.
不 不是的
No, you're not.
你见到了我们的未来
You've seen what we become.
星云 听她的话
Nebula, listen to her.
你可以改变的
You can change.
他不会允许的
He won't let me.
不
No!
索尔 给我来一下
Okay, Thor. Hit me.
老板 醒醒
Boss, wake up!
我就知道
I knew it!
我这么多年的征服
In all my years of conquest...
暴虐
violence...
屠戮
slaughter...
从来不掺杂个人情感
it was never personal.
我现在要让你们知道…
But I'll tell you now...
我要怎么对付你们这个冥顽不化
what I'm about to do to your stubborn,
令人生厌 蝼蚁般的星球
annoying little planet...
我会享受这个过程
I'm gonna enjoy it...
特别特别地尽兴
very, very much.
队长 你能听到吗
Hey, Cap, you read me?
队长 我是山姆 你能听到吗
Cap, it's Sam. Can you hear me?
在你左侧
On your left.
必胜
就这么多人吗
Is that everyone?
什么 你还嫌少吗
What? You wanted more?
复仇者
Avengers...
集结
assemble.
把那个给我 小的你拿走
No, no, give me that. You have the little one.
天啊 你绝对想不到发生了什么
Holy cow! You will not believe what's been going on.
你还记得我们在太空里吗
Do you remember when we were in space?
然后我变成灰了
And I got all dusty?
我肯定是昏过去了
And I must've passed out,
我醒后你已经走了
because I woke up and you were gone.
但是奇异博士还在 对吧
But Doctor Strange was there, right? And he was like...
他说都五年了 去吧 去帮他们
"It's been five years. Come on, they need us."
他就耍那个金光闪闪的玩意儿
- And then he started doing the yellow sparkly thing that he does all the time. - He did? Oh, no.
你这是怎么了
What are you doing?
感觉真好
Oh, this is nice.
卡魔拉
Gamora?
我以为我失去你了
I thought I lost you.
别碰我
Don't touch me!
第一回你没踢着
You missed the first time.
第二回你可是一石二鸟
Then you got 'em both the second time.
就是他吗 不会吧
This is the one? Seriously?
你能选的除了他 就只剩一棵树了
Your choices were him or a tree.
队长 这个要命的东西该怎么办
Cap! What do you want me to do with this damn thing?
把那些原石带得越远越好
Get those stones as far away as possible!
不
No!
我们得把它们送回到原来的地方
We need to get 'em back where they came from.
它们回不去了 灭霸把量子通道毁了
No way to get 'em back. Thanos destroyed the quantum tunnel.
等等
Hold on!
我们还有其他的时间机器
That wasn't our only time machine.
有谁看见一辆棕色的破面包车了吗
Anyone see an ugly brown van out there?
看见了 但是停的地方可不怎么样
Yes! But you're not gonna like where it's parked!
斯科特 你多长时间能启动那玩意儿
Scott, how long you need to get that thing working?
大概十分钟
Uh, maybe 10 minutes.
启动机器 我们把原石带给你
Get it started. We'll get the stones to you.
好的 队长
We're on it, Cap.
你说我们有一千四百万分之一的几率能赢
You said one out of 14 million, we win, yeah?
是这次吗
Tell me this is it.
我要是说了
If I tell you what happens...
就不会发生了
it won't happen.
希望你是对的
You better be right.
这里乱七八糟
It's a mess back here.
启动不了
It's dead.
- 什么 - 启动不了
- What? - It's dead.
我只能硬来了
I have to hot-wire it.
星云在哪里
Where's Nebula?
她没有回应
She's not responding.
大人
Sire...
克林特
Clint!
交给我
Give it to me.
你夺走了我的一切
You took everything from me.
我根本不认识你
I don't even know who you are.
你会认识的
You will.
我拿到了
I got it!
启动一击必杀模式
Activate Instant Kill.
炮雨齐射
Rain fire!
大人 我们的部队…
But, sire, our troops!
快发射
Just do it!
这边有情况
Uh, is anyone else seeing this?
我搞得定 我搞得定
I got this!
好吧 我搞不定
I got this. Okay, I don't got this.
救命啊
Help, somebody help!
皇后区的小子 抬头
Hey, Queens, heads up!
坚持住 我抓住你了 孩子
Hang on. I got you, kid.
很高兴认识你
Hey! Nice to meet you...
天啊
Oh, my God!
发生了什么
What the hell is this?
星期五 他们朝什么开火
Friday, what are they firing at?
有东西正在穿过大气层
Something just entered the upper atmosphere.
丹佛斯 我们需要援助
Danvers, we need an assist here.
你好 我是彼得·帕克
Hi, I'm Peter Parker.
你好 彼得·帕克
Hey, Peter Parker.
你有什么要给我的吗
You got something for me?
你一个人能应付得了吗
I don't know how you're gonna get it through all of that.
别担心
Don't worry.
她不是一个人
She's got help.
我就是…天命
I am inevitable.
我…
And I...
就是…
am...
钢铁侠
Iron Man.
史塔克先生
Mr. Stark?
史塔克先生 你能听见吗
Mr. Stark. Can you hear me?
我是彼得
It's Peter.
我们赢了 史塔克先生
We won, Mr. Stark.
我们赢了 你成功了 你成功了
We won! You did it, sir, you did it.
对不起 托尼
I'm sorry. Tony.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 佩珀
Hey, Pep.
星期五
Friday?
生命垂危
Life functions critical.
托尼
Tony?
看着我
Look at me.
我们会没事儿的
We're gonna be okay.
你现在可以休息了
You can rest now.
每个人都渴望美好的结局 对吧
Everybody wants a happy ending, right?
但是现实并不总是尽如人意
But it doesn't always roll that way.
也许这一次
Maybe this time.
我希望在看到这个的时候
I'm hoping if you play this back...
你们是在庆祝
it's in celebration.
我希望家人再次团聚 我希望一切恢复如初
I hope families are reunited. I hope we get it back.
我希望这个星球能重回正轨
And something like a normal version of the planet has been restored.
如果可以的话
If there ever was such a thing.
天啊 这个世界多美好 还有整个宇宙
God, what a world. Universe, now.
如果十年前告诉我 宇宙中我们并不孤单
If you told me 10 years ago that we weren't alone...
更不用说还有后来的这些事儿
let alone to this extent, I mean,
我可能就不会那么大惊小怪了
I wouldn't have been surprised...
但是话说回来 谁又能知道呢
but come on, who knew?
光明和黑暗的强大力量己经现身了
The epic forces of darkness and light that have come into play.
结果是好是坏
And for better or worse...
那就是摩根长大以后
that's the reality Morgan's gonna
需要自己去探索的现实了
have to find a way to grow up in.
所以我觉得应该提前录下这些
So, I thought I'd probably better record a little greeting...
以免我不幸身亡 毕竟对我来说
in the case of an untimely death. On my part.
死亡不是什么意外的事儿
Not that death at any time isn't untimely.
明天我们要进行的这个时空穿梭
This time travel thing that we're gonna try and pull off tomorrow...
还真的让我担心最后能不能活下来
it's got me scratching my head about the survivability of it all.
就是这么回事
That's the thing.
不过这就是英雄的使命
Then again, that's the hero gig, right?
辉煌过后终将落幕
Part of the journey is the end.
我又何必庸人自扰呢
What am I even tripping for?
万事万物自有其道
Everything is gonna work out exactly the way it's supposed to.
我爱你三千遍
I love you 3,000.
托尼·史塔克 有一颗温暖的心
我真希望能让她知道
You know, I wish there was a way that I could let her know.
我们赢了
That we won.
我们成功了
We did it.
她知道的
She knows.
他们两个都知道
They both do.
你怎么样 小可爱
How you doing, squirt?
挺好的
Good.
你没事儿吧
You good?
你饿不饿
Good. You hungry?
你想吃什么
What do you want?
芝士汉堡
Cheeseburgers.
你爸爸最喜欢芝士汉堡
You know, your dad liked cheeseburgers.
好吧
Okay.
你想要多少芝士汉堡都可以
I'm gonna get you
好啊
all the cheeseburgers you want.
所以…
So...
你打算什么时候回来
when can we expect you back?
说到这个
Um, about that...
索尔 你的人民需要一个国王
Thor, your people need a king.
不 他们己经有了
No, they already have one.
别闹了
That's funny.
你是认真的
Are you being serious?
现在我要去做自己想做的事儿
It's time for me to be who I am...
而不是应该做的事儿
rather than who I'm supposed to be.
而你…你是个领导者
But you, you're a leader.
那才是真正的你
That's who you are.
我会让这里有很大变化的
You know, I'd make a lot of changes around here.
我很期待
I'm counting on it...
女王陛下
Your Majesty.
你要去做什么
What will you do?
还不确定
I'm not sure.
一千年以来 这是我第一次没有方向
For the first time in a thousand years, I have no path.
但我可以搭个顺风车
I do have a ride though.
再不走就不等了 胖子
Move it or lose it, hairbag.
正在搜索
好啦 开始吧
Oh, here we are!
小树苗 真高兴见到你
Tree, good to see you.
银河阿斯加德护卫队又团聚了
The Asgardians of the Galaxy back together again.
我们先去哪儿
Where to first?
我先声明 这还是我的船 我说了算
Just so you know, this is my ship still. I'm in charge.
我知道 我知道 当然你说了算
I know. I know. Of course you are.
当然了
Of course.
你一边说着当然了一边又按地图去了
See, you say, "Of course," but then you touch the map.
我认为你并不是真心觉得是我说了算
It makes you think that maybe you didn't realize I was in charge.
龟儿 那是你自己心里缺乏安全感
Quail, that's your own insecurities in there.
什么龟儿
Quail?
我只是在试着做好服务和协助而己
Okay? I am merely trying to be of service and assisting.
是奎尔
Quill.
我说的就是这个
That's what I said.
你们应该打一架 赢的说了算
You should fight one another for the honor of leadership.
这主意好
Sounds fair.
- 没这个必要吧 - 没必要 同意
- It's not necessary, okay? - It's not.
我这儿有枪 还是你们想用刀
I got some blasters, unless you guys wanna use knives.
太棒了一定要用刀
Oh, yes! Please, use knives.
那就用刀
Yeah. Knives.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
真没必要 没必要
Not necessary.
谁也不用捅谁
There shall be no knifing one another.
大家都知道是谁说了算
Everybody knows who's in charge.
是我
Me.
对不对
Right?
对 是你
Yes, you.
当然是你 当然了
Of course! Of course.
当然
Of course.
记住
Remember...
原石必须送回准确的时刻
you have to return the stones
否则就会出现
to the exact moment you got 'em...
一大堆麻烦的多重现实
or you're gonna open up a bunch of nasty alternative realities.
别担心 布鲁斯
Don't worry, Bruce.
我会搞定的
Clip all the branches.
我试过了
You know, I tried.
当我戴上手套用原石的时候
When I had the gauntlet, the stones,
我真的试着想把她带回来
I really tried to bring her back.
我很想她
I miss her, man.
我也一样
Me too.
如果需要我可以和你一起去
You know, if you want, I could come with you.
谢谢你 山姆
You're a good man, Sam.
这次还是我来吧
This one's on me, though.
我回来之前别做傻事儿
Don't do anything stupid till I get back.
怎么会 傻事儿都让你做了
How can I? You're taking all the stupid with you.
我会想念你的 兄弟
Gonna miss you, buddy.
放心吧 巴基
It's gonna be okay, Buck.
大概需要多长时间
How long is this gonna take?
对他而言 多久都可以 对我们而言 五秒钟
For him, as long as he needs. For us, five seconds.
你准备好了吗 队长
You ready, Cap?
我们等你回来
All right, we'll meet you back here, okay?
没问题
You bet.
启动量子领域 三
Going quantum. Three...
二 一
two, one.
然后准备回来 五
And returning in five...
四 三 二一
four, three, two, one.
他人呢
Where is he?
我不知道 时间戳己经同步了
I don't know. He blew right by his time stamp.
他应该回来了才对
He should be here.
把他弄回来
Get him back.
- 我在努力 - 快把他弄回来
- I'm trying. - Get him the hell back.
- 我说了我在努力 - 山姆
- Hey, I said I'm trying. - Sam.
过去吧
Go ahead.
队长
Cap?
你好 山姆
Hi, Sam.
所以是出了差错 还是本意如此
So, did something go wrong or did something go right?
在我把原石还回去以后 我想…
Well, after I put the stones back, I thought...
也许应该试试
maybe...
托尼劝我过的那种人生
I'll try some of that life Tony was telling me to get.
结果怎么样
How'd that work out for ya?
非常美好
It was beautiful.
我为你高兴 真的
Good. I'm happy for you. Truly.
谢谢你
Thank you.
唯一让我难过的就是…
Only thing bumming me out...
我的世界里不再有美国队长了
is the fact I have to live in a world without Captain America.
对了
Oh.
你提醒了我
That reminds me.
戴上试试
Try it on.
感觉如何
How does it feel?
感觉好像是别人的
Like it's someone else's.
它不是别人的
It isn't.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我会尽力的
I'll do my best.
所以它属于你了
That's why it's yours.
想和我聊聊她吗
You wanna tell me about her?
不
No.
不用了
No, I don't think I will.
导 演
安东尼·罗素   乔·罗素
编 剧
克里斯托弗·马库斯
斯蒂芬·麦克菲利
制 片
凯文·费奇
执行制片
路易斯·斯波西托
维多利亚·阿隆索
执行制片
迈克尔·格里洛
陈 贞
执行制片
乔恩·费儒
詹姆斯·古恩
斯坦·李
联合制片
米奇·贝尔
克里斯托弗·马库斯
斯蒂芬·麦克菲利
改编自漫威漫画 作者
斯坦·李   杰克·科比
摄影导演
特伦特·欧派洛克
艺术指导
查尔斯·伍德
剪 辑
杰弗里·福特
马修·施密特
服装设计
茱迪安娜·马科夫斯基
视觉特效总监
丹·迪利奥
高级视觉特效总监
仁·昂德达尔
视觉特效制作
丽萨·玛拉
音 乐
亚伦·史维斯查
音乐总监
戴夫·乔丹
选 角
萨拉·芬恩
唐·钱德尔  饰  詹姆斯·罗德/战争机器
保罗·路德  饰  斯科特·朗/蚁人
本尼迪克特·康伯巴奇  饰  史蒂芬·斯特兰奇/奇异博士
查德维克·博斯曼  饰  特查拉/黑豹
布丽·拉尔森  饰  卡罗尔·丹弗斯/惊奇队长
汤姆·赫兰德  饰  彼得·帕克/蜘蛛侠
凯伦·吉兰  饰  星云
佐伊·索尔达娜  饰  卡魔拉
伊万杰琳·莉莉  饰  霍普·凡·戴恩/黄蜂女
泰莎·汤普森  饰  女武神
蕾妮·罗素  饰  弗丽嘉
伊丽莎白·奥尔森  饰  旺达·马克西莫夫/猩红女巫
安东尼·麦凯  饰  山姆·威尔逊/猎鹰
塞巴斯蒂安·斯坦  饰  巴基·巴恩斯/冬兵
汤姆·希德勒斯顿  饰  洛基
达娜·古瑞拉  饰  奥克耶
本尼迪特·王  饰  王
庞·克莱门捷夫  饰  曼蒂斯
戴夫·巴蒂斯塔  饰  德拉克斯
莱蒂希娅·赖特  饰  苏睿
约翰·斯拉特里  饰  霍华德·史塔克
蒂尔达·斯文顿  饰  古一
乔恩·费儒  饰  哈皮
海莉·阿特维尔  饰  玛格丽特·卡特
娜塔莉·波特曼  饰  简·福斯特
玛丽莎·托梅  饰  梅·帕克
塔伊加·维迪提  饰  科恩格
安吉拉·贝塞特  饰  拉曼达
迈克尔·道格拉斯  饰  汉克·皮姆
米歇尔·菲佛  饰  珍妮·凡·戴恩
威廉·赫特  饰  国务卿
寇碧·史莫德斯  饰  特工希尔
西恩·古恩  饰  克拉格林
温斯顿·杜克  饰  姆巴库
琳达·卡德里尼  饰  劳拉
麦克斯米利安诺·贺南德兹  饰  希特维尔
弗兰克·格里罗  饰  朗姆洛/交叉骨
真田广之  饰  铃木
汤姆·沃恩·劳勒  饰  黑舌谋士
詹姆斯·达西  饰  贾维斯
雅各·巴塔伦  饰  奈德
范·迪塞尔 配音 格鲁特
布莱德利·库珀 配音 火箭浣熊
格温妮丝·帕特洛  饰  佩珀·波兹
罗伯特·雷德福  饰  亚历山大·皮尔斯
乔什·布洛林  饰  灭霸
克里斯·帕拉特  饰  彼得·奎尔/星爵
塞缪尔·杰克逊  饰  尼克·弗瑞
杰瑞米·雷纳  饰  克林特·巴顿/鹰眼
斯嘉丽·约翰逊  饰  娜塔莎·罗曼诺夫/黑寡妇
克里斯·海姆斯沃斯  饰  索尔/雷神
马克·鲁法洛  饰  布鲁斯·班纳/浩克
克里斯·埃文斯  饰  史蒂夫·罗杰斯/美国队长
小罗伯特·唐尼  饰  托尼·史塔克/钢铁侠
中文字幕
中国大陆官方译本
英文字幕
iTunes官方字幕
双语合成
CHAOSPACE布布
后期
蓝光版特效字幕 请关注
微博@chaospace2019
更多优质特效字幕 请访问
CHAOSPACE.FUN
更多特效字幕尽在